<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Contribute on Jenkins X</title>
    <link>http://jenkins-x.io/zh/categories/contribute/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Contribute on Jenkins X</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-CN</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jenkins-x.io/zh/categories/contribute/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Contribute to the Documentation</title>
      <link>http://jenkins-x.io/zh/contribute/documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jenkins-x.io/zh/contribute/documentation/</guid>
      <description>Create Your Fork It&amp;rsquo;s best to make changes to the Jenkins X docs on your local machine to check for consistent visual styling. Make sure you&amp;rsquo;ve created a fork of jx-docs on GitHub and cloned the repository locally on your machine. For more information, you can see GitHub&amp;rsquo;s documentation on &amp;ldquo;forking&amp;rdquo; or follow along with Jenkins X&amp;rsquo;s development contribution guide.
You can then create a separate branch for your additions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contribute to the code</title>
      <link>http://jenkins-x.io/zh/contribute/development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jenkins-x.io/zh/contribute/development/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Jenkins X is an open-source project and lives by the work of its contributors. There are plenty of open issues, and we need your help to make Jenkins X even more awesome. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to be a Go guru to contribute to the project&amp;rsquo;s development.
Assumptions This contribution guide takes a step-by-step approach in hopes of helping newcomers. Therefore, we only assume the following:
 You are new to Git or open-source projects in general You are a fan of Jenkins X and enthusiastic about contributing to the project   If you&amp;rsquo;re struggling at any point in this contribution guide, reach out to the Jenkins X community in Jenkins X&amp;rsquo;s Discussion forum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>给 Jenkins X 项目做贡献</title>
      <link>http://jenkins-x.io/zh/contribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jenkins-x.io/zh/contribute/</guid>
      <description>Jenkins X relies heavily on the enthusiasm and participation of the open-source community. We need your help so please dive in! There are many ways to help:
 Give us feedback. What could we improve? Anything you don&amp;rsquo;t like or you think is missing? Help improve the documentation so its more clear how to get started and use Jenkins X Add your own quickstarts so the Jenkins X community can easily bootstrap new projects using your quickstart.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>