<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Contribute on Jenkins X</title>
    <link>https://jenkins-x.io/zh/categories/contribute/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Contribute on Jenkins X</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-CN</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jenkins-x.io/zh/categories/contribute/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>给 Jenkins X 项目做贡献</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/zh/contribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/zh/contribute/</guid>
      <description>Jenkins X relies heavily on the enthusiasm and participation of the open-source community. We need your help so please dive in! There are many ways to help:
 Give us feedback. What could we improve? Anything you don&amp;rsquo;t like or you think is missing? Help improve the documentation so its more clear how to get started and use Jenkins X Add your own quickstarts so the Jenkins X community can easily bootstrap new projects using your quickstart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>贡献代码</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/zh/contribute/development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/zh/contribute/development/</guid>
      <description>介绍 Jenkins X is an open-source project and lives by the work of its contributors. There are plenty of open issues, and we need your help to make Jenkins X even more awesome. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to be a Go guru to contribute to the project&amp;rsquo;s development.
假设 This contribution guide takes a step-by-step approach in hopes of helping newcomers. Therefore, we only assume the following:
 You are new to Git or open-source projects in general You are a fan of Jenkins X and enthusiastic about contributing to the project   If you&amp;rsquo;re struggling at any point in this contribution guide, reach out to the Jenkins X community in Jenkins X&amp;rsquo;s Discussion forum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>文档贡献</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/zh/contribute/documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/zh/contribute/documentation/</guid>
      <description>创建派生库 最好在你本地的机器上修改 Jenkins X 文档，检查视觉风格一致。确保你已经在 Github 上派生了 jx-docs，并在你的机器上克隆了这个库。更多信息，你可以查看 GitHub 的&amp;rdquo;派生&amp;rdquo;文档 或者按照 Jenkins X 开发贡献指导。
然后，你可以创建一个独立的分支。一定要选择符合内容类型的描述性分支名称。下面的一个示例分支的名称，你可以用于添加一个新的网站用于展示：
git checkout -b jon-doe-showcase-addition  添加新的内容 Jenkins X 文档重用 Jenkins X 的[骨架][]特点。在 Jenkins X 文档中所有内容章节都分配了骨架。
向 Jenkins X 中添加新的内容遵循下面相似的模式，不用考虑内容章节：
hugo new &amp;lt;DOCS-SECTION&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;new-content-lowercase&amp;gt;.md  语法标准 Jenkins X 文档中所有的页面，使用典型的三个反引号这样的语法。如果你不想花额外的时间来遵循下面的代码块简码，请使用标准的 Github 风格的 markdown。Jenkins X 使用 highlight.js 的一组语言。
你可选的语言是 xml/html, go/golang, md/markdown/mkd, handlebars, apache, toml, yaml, json, css, asciidoc, ruby, powershell/ps, scss, sh/zsh/bash/git, http/https, 和 javascript/js.
&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Hello world!&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;  代码块简码 Jenkins X 文档带有强大的简码，用于增加交互式的代码块。</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>