<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fundamentals on Jenkins X</title>
    <link>http://jenkins-x.io/categories/fundamentals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fundamentals on Jenkins X</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jenkins-x.io/categories/fundamentals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Architecture</title>
      <link>http://jenkins-x.io/architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jenkins-x.io/architecture/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concepts</title>
      <link>http://jenkins-x.io/about/concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jenkins-x.io/about/concepts/</guid>
      <description>Jenkins X is designed to make it simple for developers to work to DevOps principles and best practices.
Principles &amp;ldquo;DevOps is a set of practices intended to reduce the time between committing a change to a system and the change being placed into normal production, while ensuring high quality.&amp;rdquo;
The goals of DevOps projects are:
 Faster time to market Improved deployment frequency Shorter time between fixes Lower failure rate of releases Faster Mean Time To Recovery  High performing teams should be able to deploy multiple times per day compared to the industry average that falls between once per week and once per month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Quickstart</title>
      <link>http://jenkins-x.io/developing/create-quickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jenkins-x.io/developing/create-quickstart/</guid>
      <description>Quickstarts are pre-made applications you can start a project from, instead of starting from scratch.
You can create new applications from our list of curated Quickstart applications via the jx create quickstart command.
$ jx create quickstart You are then prompted for a list of quickstarts to choose from.
If you know the language you wish to use you can filter the list of quickstarts shown via:
$ jx create quickstart -l go Or use a text filter to filter on the project names:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Spring Boot</title>
      <link>http://jenkins-x.io/developing/create-spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jenkins-x.io/developing/create-spring/</guid>
      <description>If you are developing Java microservices then you may well be using the popular Spring Boot.
You can create new Spring Boot applications using the Spring Boot Initializr and then import them into Jenkins X via the jx import command.
However another alternative is to use the jx create spring command which provides a fast automated path.
There is a demo of using the command: jx create spring or you can try it out yourself in a terminal:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demos</title>
      <link>http://jenkins-x.io/demos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jenkins-x.io/demos/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Features</title>
      <link>http://jenkins-x.io/about/features/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jenkins-x.io/about/features/</guid>
      <description>Command Line Jenkins X comes with a handy jx command line tool to easily:
 install Jenkins X inside your existing kubernetes cluster create a new kubernetes cluster and install Jenkins X into it import projects into Jenkins X and their Continuous Delivery pipelines setup create new Spring Boot applications which get imported into Jenkins X and their Continuous Delivery pipelines setup  Pipelines Rather than having to have deep knowledge of the internals of Jenkins Pipeline, Jenkins X will default awesome pipelines for your projects that implements fully CI and CD using DevOps best practices</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Started</title>
      <link>http://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>First you will need to get the jx command line tool locally on your machine.
You can use the jx command line to create a new kubernetes cluster and have Jenkins X automatically installed.
Or if you have an existing kubernetes cluster then install Jenkins X on your kubernetes cluster</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roadmap</title>
      <link>http://jenkins-x.io/contribute/roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jenkins-x.io/contribute/roadmap/</guid>
      <description>Feature Not Planned Planned In Progress Released     Operating Systems       macOs    1.1.x   Linux    1.1.x   Windows  Planned     Cloud Providers       AWS    1.1.x   Azure    1.1.x   EKS  Planned     GKE    1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>