<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jenkins X - Cloud Native CI/CD Built On Kubernetes – About</title>
    <link>https://jenkins-x.io/v3/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About on Jenkins X - Cloud Native CI/CD Built On Kubernetes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://jenkins-x.io/v3/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>V3: What is Jenkins X?</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/v3/about/what/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/v3/about/what/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Jenkins X automates and accelerates Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery for developers on the cloud, so they can focus on building awesome software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Embracing popular open source projects Jenkins X automates the setup and management to provide an integrated Cloud Native solution teams can use to develop better software faster and more reliably than traditional non cloud solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open Source projects that Jenkins X integrates with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io/&#34;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; target platform Jenkins X is installed onto, optionally deploy and run applications built with Jenkins X&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tekton.dev/&#34;&gt;Tekton&lt;/a&gt; Cloud Native pipeline orchestration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kuberhealthy/kuberhealthy&#34;&gt;Kuberhealthy&lt;/a&gt; Periodic health checks of the systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://grafana.com&#34;&gt;Grafana&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;[optional]&lt;/strong&gt; Centralised logs and Observability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jenkins.io/&#34;&gt;Jenkins&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;[optional]&lt;/strong&gt; traditional pipeline orchestration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sonatype.com/nexus/repository-oss&#34;&gt;Nexus&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;[optional]&lt;/strong&gt; artifact repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a high level Jenkins X can be split into a few areas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;infrastructure&#34;&gt;Infrastructure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jenkins X aims to use the cloud well, Kubernetes to host the core services, storage buckets for long term storage, container registries and hosted services like secrets managers. All of this needs to be created and managed.  Jenkins X defers to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.terraform.io/&#34;&gt;Terraform&lt;/a&gt; to setup and manage the Cloud infrastructure needed by Jenkins X.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gitops&#34;&gt;GitOps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire Jenkins X experience is based around Git.  The installation, extensions and applications you develop are managed via a cluster Git repository which is the desired state of your Kubernetes cluster.  A Kubernetes operator runs inside the cluster and polls for changes in the Git repository, applying verified and approved updates.  The cluster Git repository uses &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/roboll/helmfile/&#34;&gt;Helmfile&lt;/a&gt; to describe the helm charts that should be used to install software.  Jenkins X generates the Kubernetes resources defined in the Helmfiles, commits back to Git so the exact state can always be seen via Git.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using GitOps means familiar processes can be followed when making any change to the cluster, using reviews, automation, traceability and rollbacks to give better control over consuming changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jenkins X also uses GitOps as the way to &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/admin/setup/upgrades&#34;&gt;upgrade&lt;/a&gt;, including new releases of images, helm charts and packages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;secret-management&#34;&gt;Secret Management&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using GitOps as above does present a challenge of where to store secrets for your cluster as keeping them in Git is insecure.  There is a way to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bitnami-labs/sealed-secrets&#34;&gt;encrypt secrets and store them in Git&lt;/a&gt; but there is a usability issue which makes the approach non trivial to use.  Jenkins X prefers to work with real secret provider solutions like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vaultproject.io/&#34;&gt;Vault&lt;/a&gt; or where possible cloud hosted solutions like &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloud.google.com/secret-manager&#34;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, Azure or Amazon Secrets managers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jenkins X GitOps works with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/external-secrets/kubernetes-external-secrets&#34;&gt;External Secrets&lt;/a&gt; to provide an integrated experience so your secrets source of truth is a secrets manager and the values are replicated into the cluster when needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pipelines&#34;&gt;Pipelines&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default Jenkins X ships with Tekton for a clean declarative cloud native way to describe &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/pipelines/&#34;&gt;pipelines&lt;/a&gt;.  Combined with Lighthouse Jenkins X makes it easy to inherit versioned shared pipeline steps via Git and a simple syntax providing flexibility and easy maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jenkins X can also work well with Jenkins for users that have traditional workloads.  This is not installed by default but with Jenkins X it is easy to install any helm chart and so designed to work great with our inspirational project Jenkins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chatops&#34;&gt;ChatOps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the ever growing number of microservices needing automation, Jenkins X provides the ability to interact with pipelines via comments on pull requests.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/lighthouse&#34;&gt;Lighthouse&lt;/a&gt; has evolved from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes/test-infra/tree/master/prow#&#34;&gt;Prow&lt;/a&gt; which is used heavily in the Kubernetes ecosystem to provide a consistent developer workflow for triggering tests, approvals, hold and other common commands developers use in their everyday activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;developer-experience&#34;&gt;Developer experience&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with ChatOps mentioned above Jenkins X aims to help developers have a consistent way of working with their microservices, using a CLI or GUI developers can leverage proven approaches recomended by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Accelerate-Software-Performing-Technology-Organizations/dp/1942788339&#34;&gt;Accelerate book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether creating or importing new projects that automates the setup of CI and CD, packaging applications so they can deploy and run on Kubernetes or simply release as libraries for downstream applications to use.  Jenkins X helps teams have consistency in the way they are built, developed and improved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;jx&lt;/code&gt; CLI helps developers interact with Jenkins X using their terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/ui&#34;&gt;For GUI&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt;, Jenkins X has a plugin for &lt;a href=&#34;https://octant.dev/&#34;&gt;Octant&lt;/a&gt;.  Octant runs outside of the cluster and uses the authentication and permissions users have to interact with Kubernetes resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also a read only in cluster pipeline dashboard that links via pull requests so users can view logs of builds.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>V3: Jenkins X concept models</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/v3/about/concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/v3/about/concepts/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;This is a conceptual description of the moving parts of Jenkins X.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>V3: Overview</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/v3/about/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/v3/about/overview/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Jenkins X 3.x creates clearer separation of concerns between conceptual areas and releasable components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&#34;border:none&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; src=&#34;https://whimsical.com/embed/SnJBgXG6jz9pqQewiDTNRt@2Ux7TurymNDXVRa4FpLk&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;demo&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following demo walks you through an overview of the architecture:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bVp5_tZ21AA&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;microservices&#34;&gt;Microservices&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jenkins X uses the following microservices by namespace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that if you have a working Jenkins X installation you can browse all the actual kubernetes resources used across each namespace via the &lt;code&gt;config-root/namespaces/$namespace/$chartName&lt;/code&gt; folder in your cluster git repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;jx-git-operator&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;jx-git-operator&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contains the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/about/how-it-works/#git-operator&#34;&gt;git operator&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx-git-operator&#34;&gt;jenkins-x/git-operator&lt;/a&gt; microservice and the associated &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/about/how-it-works/#boot-job&#34;&gt;boot jobs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;jx&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;jx&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contains the main development services of Jenkins X:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jx-build-controller&lt;/strong&gt; watches for &lt;code&gt;PipelineRun&lt;/code&gt; resources and creates/updates the associated &lt;code&gt;PipelineActivity&lt;/code&gt; resources used by &lt;code&gt;jx get build log&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/ui/octant&#34;&gt;octant&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/ui/dashboard&#34;&gt;pipelines visualizer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jx-pipelines-visualizer&lt;/strong&gt; visualises &lt;code&gt;PipelineActivity&lt;/code&gt; resources and the associated build logs in a read only UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jx-preview-gc-jobs&lt;/strong&gt; periodically garbage collects &lt;code&gt;Preview&lt;/code&gt; resources and their associated preview environments created by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx-preview&#34;&gt;jx preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jxboot-helmfile-resources-gcactivities&lt;/strong&gt; periodically garbage collects old and completed &lt;code&gt;PipelineActivity&lt;/code&gt; resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jxboot-helmfile-resources-gcpods&lt;/strong&gt; periodically garbage collects completed &lt;code&gt;Pods&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jx-kh-check&lt;/strong&gt; supports additional &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Comcast/kuberhealthy&#34;&gt;kuberhealthy&lt;/a&gt; based &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/guides/health/&#34;&gt;health checks&lt;/a&gt; for Jenkins X specific resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lighthouse&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;lighthouse&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/lighthouse&#34;&gt;jenkins-x/lighthouse&lt;/a&gt; creates &lt;a href=&#34;https://tekton.dev/&#34;&gt;tekton pipelines&lt;/a&gt; and triggers &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/docs/resources/faq/using/chatops/&#34;&gt;ChatOps&lt;/a&gt; on Pull Requests. Its made up of the following components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lighthouse-webhooks&lt;/strong&gt; converts webhooks from your git provider into &lt;code&gt;LighthouseJob&lt;/code&gt; custom resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lighthouse-tekton-controller&lt;/strong&gt; converts &lt;code&gt;LighthouseJob&lt;/code&gt; custom resources into &lt;a href=&#34;https://tekton.dev/&#34;&gt;tekton&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;PipelineRun&lt;/code&gt; resources (the &lt;a href=&#34;https://tekton.dev/&#34;&gt;tekton controller&lt;/a&gt; converts &lt;code&gt;PipelineRun&lt;/code&gt; resources into kubernetes &lt;code&gt;Pods&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lighthouse-foghorn&lt;/strong&gt; watches the execution of &lt;code&gt;PipelineRun&lt;/code&gt; resources triggered by lighthouse and updates the pipeline status in git so that you see pipelines start, complete or fail on your git provider along with having links the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/ui/dashboard&#34;&gt;pipelines visualizer&lt;/a&gt; on each context on a Pull Request&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lighthouse-keeper&lt;/strong&gt; looks for open Pull Requests with green pipelines and the necessary &lt;strong&gt;approve&lt;/strong&gt; labels to be able to auto merge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lighthouse-gc-jobs&lt;/strong&gt; periodically garbage collects &lt;code&gt;LighthouseJob&lt;/code&gt; resources and their associated resources (e.g. &lt;code&gt;PipelineRun&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Pods&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the following are optional extras:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/bucketrepo&#34;&gt;bucket repository&lt;/a&gt; a lightweight cloud native artifact, chart repository and maven proxy that can be configured to use cloud storage. It&amp;rsquo;s a lightweight cloud native alternative to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sonatype.com/nexus/repository-oss&#34;&gt;nexus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/helm/chartmuseum&#34;&gt;chart museum&lt;/a&gt; an optional chart repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sonatype.com/nexus/repository-oss&#34;&gt;nexus&lt;/a&gt; if used as an artifact repository and maven proxy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kuberhealthy&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;kuberhealthy&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contains the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Comcast/kuberhealthy&#34;&gt;kuberhealthy&lt;/a&gt; service to support &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/guides/health/&#34;&gt;health and improve observability&lt;/a&gt; which used by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x-plugins/jx-health&#34;&gt;jx health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;nginx&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;nginx&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contains the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/helm/charts/tree/master/stable/nginx-ingress&#34;&gt;nginx-ingress&lt;/a&gt; provider if enabled&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;jx-vault&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;jx-vault&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the following are optional extras if not using your cloud providers native secret manager:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vault-operator&lt;/strong&gt; contains the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bank-vaults.dev/docs/operator/&#34;&gt;vault operator&lt;/a&gt; which converts &lt;code&gt;Vault&lt;/code&gt; resources into instances of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vaultproject.io/&#34;&gt;HashiCorp Vault&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vault-instance&lt;/strong&gt; contains the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x-charts/vault-instance&#34;&gt;vault instance&lt;/a&gt; which creates the default &lt;code&gt;Vault&lt;/code&gt; resource&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;secret-infra&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;secret-infra&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kubernetes-external-secrets&lt;/strong&gt; contains the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/external-secrets/kubernetes-external-secrets&#34;&gt;external-secrets/kubernetes-external-secrets&lt;/a&gt; service for handling &lt;code&gt;ExternalSecrets&lt;/code&gt;. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/guides/secrets/&#34;&gt;how we use secrets&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pusher-wave&lt;/strong&gt; contains the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pusher/wave&#34;&gt;pusher/wave&lt;/a&gt; service for performing a rolling upgrade of any microservice which consumes &lt;code&gt;Secret&lt;/code&gt; resources from either vault or a cloud providers secret store and the secrets change in the underlying store&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tekton-pipelines&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;tekton-pipelines&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contains the &lt;a href=&#34;https://tekton.dev/&#34;&gt;tekton pipelines&lt;/a&gt; controllers&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>V3: Changes</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/v3/about/changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/v3/about/changes/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;You may also find the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/community/roadmap/&#34;&gt;Roadmap&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/about/maturity-matrix/&#34;&gt;Maturity Matrix&lt;/a&gt; documents useful:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;breaking-changes&#34;&gt;Breaking Changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we have &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx/issues/7870&#34;&gt;noticed a regression&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/admin/setup/upgrades/cluster/#automatic-upgrades&#34;&gt;auto upgrade jobs&lt;/a&gt; which causes them to fail with an error like this:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;updatebot WARNING: no $GIT_SECRET_MOUNT_PATH environment variable set                      
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;updatebot error: failed to setup git: failed to clone the cluster git URL: failed to clone cluster git repository https://github.com/myorg/myrepo.git: failed to clone cluster git repo https://github.com/
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;updatebot fatal: could not read Username &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;https://github.com&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;: No such device or address
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;you can fix this by following the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx/issues/7870&#34;&gt;workarounds on this issue&lt;/a&gt; which should get you past this and working &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/admin/setup/upgrades/cluster/#automatic-upgrades&#34;&gt;auto upgrade jobs&lt;/a&gt; again&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we now default to using &lt;code&gt;Ingress&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;v1&lt;/code&gt; which was introduced in kubernetes 1.19. The &lt;code&gt;v1beta1&lt;/code&gt; version of &lt;code&gt;Ingress&lt;/code&gt; has been deprecated since 1.14 and is removed in 1.22. If you are on 1.18 of kubernetes you could upgrade to 1.19 or later. Otherwise you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/faq/config/ingress/#how-do-i-configure-to-use-v1beta1-ingress&#34;&gt;configure your cluster to keep on v1beta1 if you want&lt;/a&gt; until you can move forwards to 1.19 or later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the new tekton version (0.20.x) now requires kubernetes 1.17 or later. If your cluster is older and you are using the cloud just upgrade your kubernetes version before upgrading your cluster. Otherwise you may want to explicitly override your &lt;code&gt;tekton-pipeline&lt;/code&gt; version to pin it at &lt;code&gt;0.19.1&lt;/code&gt; instead in your &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jx3-gitops-repositories/jx3-kubernetes/blob/master/helmfiles/tekton-pipelines/helmfile.yaml#L12&#34;&gt;helmfiles/tekton-pipelines/helmfile.yaml&lt;/a&gt; file&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if you are upgrading from an alpha cluster you may have vault installed in the &lt;code&gt;secret-infra&lt;/code&gt; namespace. check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/faq/config/vault/#after-an-upgrade-the-boot-job-is-waiting-for-vault-in-jx-vault&#34;&gt;FAQ on vault in the wrong namespace&lt;/a&gt; for how to upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;changes&#34;&gt;Changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we have a new &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/reference/jx/pipeline/grid/&#34;&gt;jx pipeline grid&lt;/a&gt; command to easily view whats happening in your cluster on the CLI in a similar way to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/ui/octant/&#34;&gt;Octant Console&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/ui/dashboard/&#34;&gt;Dashboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/reference/&#34;&gt;reference guide&lt;/a&gt; now has a full &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/reference/jx/&#34;&gt;Command Line Reference&lt;/a&gt; for browsing the command line of the various &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x-plugins&#34;&gt;Jenkins X Plugins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is now support for &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/admin/setup/upgrades/cluster/#automatic-upgrades&#34;&gt;automatic upgrades&lt;/a&gt; where a Pull Request is automatically generated on your development cluster repository to upgrade the versions of charts in your installation. You can define the upgrade schedule and whether or not the Pull Request is auto merged or requires a manual approval/merge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A preview can fail to create for a multitude of reasons; bad helm charts, missing secrets/volumes, invalid configuration in &lt;code&gt;jx-requirements.yml&lt;/code&gt;, bad image names, no capacity on the server to name but a few. Unfortunately &lt;code&gt;helmfile sync&lt;/code&gt; does not give much information other than it succeeded of failed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to improve feedback on why some previews can fail we have added additional output in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/reference/jx/preview/create&#34;&gt;jx preview create&lt;/a&gt; command to tail the kubernetes events in the preview namespace. This basically runs &lt;code&gt;kubectl exec get event -n $PREVIEW_NAMESPACE -w&lt;/code&gt; and adds the output to the pipeline output (prefixed with &lt;code&gt;$PREVIEW_NAMESPACE:&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this means the reason for why a preview fails should appear as a kubernetes event in the pipeline log&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we have a shiny new &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/ui/slack/&#34;&gt;Slack bot for Jenkins X&lt;/a&gt; to help notify developers of failing pipelines&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;its now much easier to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx-preview#system-tests-in-previews&#34;&gt;write system tests against Preview Environments&lt;/a&gt; so it&amp;rsquo;s easier to test images and charts function as you expect inside a Pull Request before you are happy to merge the work for faster feedback&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;check out the new &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/devops/&#34;&gt;DevOps, GitOps and Cloud Native&lt;/a&gt; documentation we&amp;rsquo;re putting together based on the learnings of continuously deliverying Jenkins X with Jenkins X.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;new clusters created using Terraform that use Vault will be using the &lt;code&gt;jx-vault&lt;/code&gt; namespace to setup Vault (so that its managed by Terraform)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;you can now use &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/reference/jx/pipeline/convert&#34;&gt;jx pipeline convert&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/pipelines/upgrading/#converting-older-pipelines&#34;&gt;convert any old pipelines&lt;/a&gt; across to the latest &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/pipelines/catalog/&#34;&gt;concise syntax&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we have an awesome &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/pipelines/catalog/&#34;&gt;new syntax to help share pipelines across git repositories&lt;/a&gt; that makes it easier to simplify the pipelines in each repository while keeping things vanilla Tekton YAML and letting you override and customise anything anywhere&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the boot job now upgrades the &lt;code&gt;docs&lt;/code&gt; folder to show what charts and versions are deployed in each namespace. You can view the &lt;code&gt;docs&lt;/code&gt; folder in your own git repositories once you&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/admin/setup/upgrades/cluster/&#34;&gt;upgraded your cluster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you can see the default reports for &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jx3-gitops-repositories/jx3-kubernetes/tree/master/docs&#34;&gt;kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jx3-gitops-repositories/jx3-eks-vault/tree/master/docs&#34;&gt;aws&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jx3-gitops-repositories/jx3-azure-akv&#34;&gt;azure&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jx3-gitops-repositories/jx3-gke-gsm/tree/master/docs&#34;&gt;gke&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now use multiple helmfiles per namespace so its easier to understand the organisation of your charts across namespaces&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/blog/2020/12/04/jx-v3-update/&#34;&gt;3.0 beta is almost ready&lt;/a&gt; so if you have been using the 3.0 alpha we now have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/admin/guides/migrate/v3-alpha/&#34;&gt;migration guide&lt;/a&gt; to smooth your transition to the beta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now easily open the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/ui/octant/&#34;&gt;Octant Console&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/ui/dashboard/&#34;&gt;Pipeline Dashboard&lt;/a&gt; via 2 easy commands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;jx ui
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;jx dash
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now have &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/pipelines/&#34;&gt;Tekton Catalog integration&lt;/a&gt; so that you can:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;easily &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/pipelines/#editing-pipelines&#34;&gt;edit any pipeline in any git repository&lt;/a&gt; by just modifying the &lt;code&gt;PipelineRun&lt;/code&gt; files in your &lt;code&gt;.ligthhouse/jenkins-x&lt;/code&gt; folder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/pipelines/#adding-tasks-from-the-tekton-catalog&#34;&gt;reuse Tasks from the Tekton catalog&lt;/a&gt; and optionally modify them locally in your repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/pipelines/#add-new-taskspipelines-by-hand&#34;&gt;add new pipelines to any git repository&lt;/a&gt; to reuse any &lt;code&gt;PipelineRun&lt;/code&gt; files you find from places like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tektoncd/catalog&#34;&gt;tekton catalog&lt;/a&gt; into your repositories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have migrated most of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx#plugins&#34;&gt;Jenkins X Plugins&lt;/a&gt; over to the new client-go 1.19.x version now which is a fairly major change due to the API changes in client-go. So we&amp;rsquo;ve moved many of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx#libraries&#34;&gt;libraries&lt;/a&gt; over to use &lt;code&gt;v3&lt;/code&gt; instead such as using libraries like &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx-api&#34;&gt;jx-api&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx-helpers&#34;&gt;jx-helpers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if you were planning on submitting a Pull Request on any plugin please make sure you rebase before submitting a Pull Request. Also upgrade to go &lt;code&gt;1.15.2&lt;/code&gt; ASAP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/about/maturity-matrix/&#34;&gt;Maturity Matrix&lt;/a&gt; published! You can now view at a glance the different capabilities across clouds and infrastructure. Many thanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/borntorock&#34;&gt;Nitin&lt;/a&gt; for all your hard work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preview environments now use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/roboll/helmfile&#34;&gt;helmfile&lt;/a&gt; as a declarative way to describe all of the dependencies you need in your preview environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is all handled by the new &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx-preview&#34;&gt;jx-preview&lt;/a&gt; plugin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This also opens up the possibility of using multiple namespaces per preview; or using canary releases on multiple previews into a shared environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Jenkins X version 3 CLI &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx&#34;&gt;jx&lt;/a&gt; is now plugins all the way down; so that all of the features are implemented by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx#plugins&#34;&gt;separate binary plugins&lt;/a&gt; making the CLI more modular and easier to work on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>V3: Maturity Level Matrix</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/v3/about/maturity-matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/v3/about/maturity-matrix/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/images/v3/v3-maturity.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/images/v3/jx-v3alpha-color-rep.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This maturity matrix describes the tentative plan post Jenkins X v3.0 &lt;strong&gt;GA&lt;/strong&gt; release. This matrix will continue to evolve as we progress further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/images/v3/jx-v3ga-maturity-matrix.png&#34;&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>V3: Benefits</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/v3/about/benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/v3/about/benefits/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can use vanilla tools like &lt;a href=&#34;https://helm.sh/&#34;&gt;helm 3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/roboll/helmfile&#34;&gt;helmfile&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kustomize.io/&#34;&gt;kustomize&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://googlecontainertools.github.io/kpt/&#34;&gt;kpt&lt;/a&gt; to install, update or delete charts in any namespace without needing helm 2.x or tiller or custom code to manage &lt;code&gt;helm template&lt;/code&gt;.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can avoid all the complexities of the &lt;code&gt;jx step helm apply&lt;/code&gt; logic we used in Jenkins X 2.x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instead we can replace this with vanilla &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/roboll/helmfile&#34;&gt;helmfile&lt;/a&gt; to allow optional templating of &lt;code&gt;values.yaml&lt;/code&gt; files when using helm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/admin/platform/&#34;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/a&gt; approach is much simpler, easier to configure and customise and is cleanly integrated with tools like Terraform and works well with different cloud infrastructure platforms.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The default install/upgrade pipelines check in all the generated kubernetes resources and custom resources as YAML so its easy to understand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can read more about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx-gitops/blob/master/docs/git_layout.md&#34;&gt;git layout here&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;config-root/cluster&lt;/code&gt; folder contains all the global cluster level resources like &lt;code&gt;ClusterRole&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Namespace&lt;/code&gt; or Custom Resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;config-root/namespaces/jx&lt;/code&gt; folder contains all the namespaced resources in the &lt;code&gt;jx&lt;/code&gt; namespace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This makes it easy to use flexible apply logic in different boot &lt;code&gt;Jobs&lt;/code&gt; with different RBAC (or a system admin could apply the cluster level resources for you by hand) - to make it easier to install Jenkins X on more locked down and restricted clusters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/external-secrets/kubernetes-external-secrets&#34;&gt;Kubernetes External Secrets&lt;/a&gt; to provide a single way to manage secrets which supports the following back end systems:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alibaba Cloud KMS Secret Manager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AWS Secrets Manager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Azure Key Vault&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GCP Secret Manager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hashicorp Vault&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It opens the door to a flexible &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/guides/multi-cluster/&#34;&gt;multi-cluster support&lt;/a&gt; so that every cluster can be managed in the same canonical GitOps approach from a single git repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/admin/platform/&#34;&gt;getting started approach&lt;/a&gt; runs the boot pipeline as a &lt;code&gt;Job&lt;/code&gt; inside the Kubernetes cluster. This ensures consistency in tooling used and also improves security by avoiding having the secrets on a developers laptop.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The only thing you run on your local machine when installing Jenkins X is &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/guides/operator/&#34;&gt;installing the git operator&lt;/a&gt; which is a simple helm chart.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything is now an app. So if you want to remove our &lt;code&gt;nginx-ingress&lt;/code&gt; chart and replace it with another ingress solution (knative / istio / gloo / ambassador / linkerd or whatever) just go ahead and use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/apps/&#34;&gt;apps commands&lt;/a&gt; to add/remove apps and have boot manage everything in a consistent way
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e.g. here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jx3-gitops-repositories/jx3-kind-vault/blob/master/helmfile.yaml#L17&#34;&gt;an example&lt;/a&gt; of removing &lt;code&gt;chartmusem&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;nexus&lt;/code&gt; and replacing it with &lt;code&gt;bucketrepo&lt;/code&gt; via a single simple yaml change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can install an app in a specific namespace if you wish
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This also opens the door to using boot to setup multi-team installations where multiple teams use different namespaces but share services in the same cluster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cluster GitOps repository is simpler and easier to keep in sync/rebase/merge with the upstream git repositories.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We use &lt;a href=&#34;https://googlecontainertools.github.io/kpt/&#34;&gt;kpt&lt;/a&gt; to do that for us&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We now include the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/about/concepts/version-stream/&#34;&gt;version stream&lt;/a&gt; inside your GitOps repository too inside the &lt;code&gt;versionStream&lt;/code&gt; directory after installation so that all the information about your installation is inside a single git repository so its simpler to test changes &amp;amp; ensure consistency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can avoid composite charts to simplfiy configuration and upgrades&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We no longer use &lt;code&gt;exposecontroller&lt;/code&gt;, instead use regular helm configuration to create &lt;code&gt;Ingress&lt;/code&gt; resources and &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/faq/#how-do-i-configure-the-ingress-domain-in-dev-staging-or-production&#34;&gt;override domain names&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;secret handling is currently much simpler using Kubernetes External Secrets for any secrets in any namespace or cluster for your own apps or for those used by Jenkins X.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>V3: Comparison</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/v3/about/comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/v3/about/comparison/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;This document outlines the similarities and differences of the 3.x approach for those who are aware of &lt;code&gt;jx boot&lt;/code&gt; with helm 2 in 2.x of Jenkins X.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;similarities-between-2x-and-3x&#34;&gt;Similarities between 2.x and 3.x&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like classic boot with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jenkins-x-boot-config/&#34;&gt;jenkins-x-boot-config&lt;/a&gt; git repository, this new &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/roboll/helmfile&#34;&gt;helmfile&lt;/a&gt; solution supports:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you can install and upgrade Jenkins X via GitOps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you can reuse helm charts from the internet, local charts or charts built by Jenkins X in any environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a YAML file is used to store all the charts that are applied during install/upgrade&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;differences-with-in-3x&#34;&gt;Differences with in 3.x&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we support any permutation of tools such as: &lt;a href=&#34;https://helm.sh/&#34;&gt;helm 3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/roboll/helmfile&#34;&gt;helmfile&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kustomize.io/&#34;&gt;kustomize&lt;/a&gt; and/or &lt;a href=&#34;https://googlecontainertools.github.io/kpt/&#34;&gt;kpt&lt;/a&gt; to create the kubernetes resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in 3.x the installation/upgrade of Jenkins X is run inside the kubernetes cluster via a &lt;code&gt;Job&lt;/code&gt; rather than on a developers laptop which helps with consistency and security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in 3.x we use a single git repository for each cluster; which can manage as many teams/namespaces as you like within the cluster
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;so any local environments like &lt;code&gt;Staging&lt;/code&gt; which reside in the same kubernetes cluster are defined in the same git repository in 3.x - whereas in 2.x we used a separate git repository for &lt;code&gt;Dev&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Staging&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Production&lt;/code&gt; when sharing the same cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if &lt;code&gt;Dev&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Preprod&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Production&lt;/code&gt; environments are in separate kubernetes clusters then those will have a git repository each.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;any helm chart can be deployed in any namespace (previously we used a single namespace for all charts in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jenkins-x-boot-config/blob/master/env/requirements.yaml&#34;&gt;env/requirements.yaml&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;instead of using &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jenkins-x-boot-config/blob/master/env/requirements.yaml&#34;&gt;env/requirements.yaml&lt;/a&gt; we now use a simple and more powerful &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x-labs/boot-helmfile-poc/blob/master/helmfile.yaml&#34;&gt;helmfile.yaml&lt;/a&gt; file which is similar but supports:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we can specify a &lt;code&gt;namespace&lt;/code&gt; on any chart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we can add extra &lt;code&gt;values&lt;/code&gt; files to use with the chart to override the helm &lt;code&gt;values.yaml&lt;/code&gt; files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;instead of copying lots of &lt;code&gt;env/$appName/values*.yaml&lt;/code&gt; files into the boot config like we do in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jenkins-x-boot-config/blob/master/env/&#34;&gt;these folders&lt;/a&gt; such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jenkins-x-boot-config/blob/master/env/lighthouse/values.tmpl.yaml&#34;&gt;the lighthouse/values.tmpl.yaml&lt;/a&gt; we can instead default all of these from the version stream at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jxr-versions/tree/master/apps/jenkins-x/lighthouse&#34;&gt;apps/jenkins-x/lighthouse&lt;/a&gt; - which means the boot config git repository is much simpler, we can share more configuration with the version stream and it avoids lots of git merge/rebase issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adding and removing apps in your GitOps repository causes those resources to be properly installed or uninstalled
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you can also review exactly what kubernetes resources will change on the Pull Request&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we no longer use a composite chart for &lt;code&gt;env/Chart.yaml&lt;/code&gt; and instead deploy each chart independently
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this means that each chart has its own unique version number you can see in the &lt;code&gt;helmfile.yaml&lt;/code&gt; file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we have done away with the complexity of &lt;code&gt;jenkins-x-platform&lt;/code&gt; (a composite chart containing logs of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jenkins-x-platform/blob/master/jenkins-x-platform/requirements.yaml&#34;&gt;dependencies&lt;/a&gt; like &lt;code&gt;jenkins&lt;/code&gt; + &lt;code&gt;chartmuseum&lt;/code&gt; + &lt;code&gt;nexus&lt;/code&gt; etc) so that each chart can be added/removed independently or swapped out with a different version/distribution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;removing-complexity-and-magic&#34;&gt;Removing complexity and magic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Removing complexity out of Jenkins X and reusing other solutions wherever possible.  Jenkins X 2.x was tightly coupled to helm 2 for example.  There were &lt;code&gt;jx&lt;/code&gt; CLI steps that wrapped helm commands when installing applications into the cluster which injected secrets from an internal Vault and ultimately made it very confusing for users and maintainers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jenkins X 3.x prefers to avoid wrapping other CLIs unless a consistent higher level UX is being provided say around managing secrets and underlying commands being executed are clearly printed in users terminals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;maintainability&#34;&gt;Maintainability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Created a new &lt;code&gt;jx&lt;/code&gt; CLI which includes an extensible plugin model where each main subcommand off the jx base is it&amp;rsquo;s own releasable git repository.  This has significantly improved the Jenkins X codebase which helps with maintainability and contributions.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>V3: How it works</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/v3/about/how-it-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/v3/about/how-it-works/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-works&#34;&gt;How it works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GitOps repository templates contain the source code, scripts and docs to help you get your cloud resources created (e.g. a kubernetes cluster and maybe buckets and/or a secret manager).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have created the GitOps repository from one of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/admin/platform/&#34;&gt;available templates and followed the instructions&lt;/a&gt; to set up your infrastructure you &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/guides/operator/&#34;&gt;install the git operator&lt;/a&gt; via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx-admin/blob/master/docs/cmd/jx-admin_operator.md&#34;&gt;jx admin operator&lt;/a&gt; command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    jx admin operator
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;That command essentially installs the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx-git-operator&#34;&gt;git operator&lt;/a&gt; chart, passing in the git URL, username and token to run the boot process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;git-operator&#34;&gt;Git Operator&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx-git-operator&#34;&gt;git operator&lt;/a&gt; works by polling the git repository looking for changes and running a kubernetes Job on each change. The Job resource is defined inside the git repository at &lt;strong&gt;versionStream/git-operator/job.yaml&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can view the boot Job log via the command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    jx admin log
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Or you can browse the log in the Octant UI in the operations tab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;boot-job&#34;&gt;Boot Job&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The boot job runs on startup and on any git commit to the GitOps repository you used to install the operator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The boot job is defined in &lt;strong&gt;versionStream/git-operator/job.yaml&lt;/strong&gt; in git and essentially:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Runs the generate step&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Runs the apply step&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;generate-step&#34;&gt;Generate step&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This step is run in the following situations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On startup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After each commit in a Pull Request&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whenever a commit is made to the main branch which isn’t a merge of a Pull Request merge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The generate step does the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolves any missing values (cluster information, domain name) in the &lt;strong&gt;jx-values.yaml&lt;/strong&gt; file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolves any missing versions or helm values.yaml files the &lt;strong&gt;helmfile.yaml&lt;/strong&gt; file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Runs &lt;code&gt;helmfile template&lt;/code&gt; to generate the kubernetes resources for all the charts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy all the generated resources into a tree of files in &lt;strong&gt;config-root/namespaces/myns/somechart/*.yaml&lt;/strong&gt; where
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;myns&lt;/strong&gt; is the namespace for the resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Somechart&lt;/strong&gt; is the name of the chart (or chart alias)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any &lt;strong&gt;Secret&lt;/strong&gt; resource is converted to an &lt;strong&gt;ExternalSecret&lt;/strong&gt; so that it can be checked into git
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx-secret#mappings&#34;&gt;secret mapping&lt;/a&gt; to generate &lt;strong&gt;ExternalSecret&lt;/strong&gt; resources which define where the &lt;code&gt;Secret&lt;/code&gt; will be populated from (e.g. vault or your cloud provider secret store)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;secrets can be populated by either:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;directly in the secret store (e.g. via vault or the cloud secret store directly). If you are using vault you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/guides/secrets/vault/#using-vault&#34;&gt;follow these instructions&lt;/a&gt; to access the vault UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/guides/secrets/#edit-secrets&#34;&gt;jx secret edit&lt;/a&gt; command&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/reference/jx/secret/populate&#34;&gt;jx secret populate&lt;/a&gt; command inside the boot job which uses the &lt;code&gt;versionStream/charts/*/secret-schema.yaml&lt;/code&gt; files to populate with generators and default values from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx-secret#schema&#34;&gt;secret schema files&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A few extra steps are run on the YAMLs to help deployments
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a common label so that &lt;code&gt;kubectl apply --prune --selector&lt;/code&gt; can be used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add some hashes to resources so that changes to configurations causes a rolling upgrade&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add support for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pusher/wave&#34;&gt;pusher wave&lt;/a&gt; operator so that changing of secret values (inside, say, vault or Amazon/Azure/Google secret manager) causes a rolling upgrade of pods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;apply-step&#34;&gt;Apply step&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This step is run on any commit to the main branch(after the generate step has completed).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It essentially does &lt;code&gt;kubectl apply&lt;/code&gt; of the resources in the &lt;strong&gt;config-root&lt;/strong&gt; tree in git.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The apply step could be performed by other tools if need be (e.g. Google Anthos Config Sync or flux).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;promotion&#34;&gt;Promotion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you create a quickstart or import a new project a new release is created then promotion is triggered just like in Jenkins X 2.x.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One change from Jenkins X 2.x is we default to including the specific kubernetes resources in git; rather than, say, just the name of a helm chart and the version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what tends to happen is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the promote step in a pipeline creates a Pull Request on the cluster repository for the cluster to add or upgrade a helm chart and version&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The above &lt;a href=&#34;#generate-step&#34;&gt;Generate&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;#apply-step&#34;&gt;Apply step&lt;/a&gt; runs to fill in more details to the Pull Request of the actual kubernetes resources that will be added, modified or removed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a second git commit is added to the Pull Request with the title &lt;code&gt;chore: regenerated&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;code&gt;updatebot&lt;/code&gt; label is added to the Pull Request so that the Pull Request can be considered for automatic merging if all of the git checks are green (including the Pull Request pipelines)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;once the Pull Request merges to the main branch the &lt;code&gt;git operator&lt;/code&gt; will trigger to apply the kubernetes resources to the cluster via the above apply step&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you will see 2 commits on a typical promotion pull request:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the high level change of the helm chart(s) and versions. e.g. to change &lt;code&gt;myapp&lt;/code&gt; to version &lt;code&gt;1.2.3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the detail of the actual changes that will apply to kubernetes resources. e.g. a new &lt;code&gt;Deployment&lt;/code&gt; or changes to the &lt;code&gt;image:&lt;/code&gt; of an existing &lt;code&gt;Deployment&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;importing--creating-quickstarts&#34;&gt;Importing / Creating Quickstarts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the new GitOps model this is a little more complex than in v2 since imports are done via GitOps and the changes in git result in a Job / Pipeline running in the cluster to effect change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the steps involved in &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/create-project/&#34;&gt;creating projects&lt;/a&gt; via importing / creating quickstarts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run the &lt;code&gt;jx project quickstart&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;jx project import&lt;/code&gt; command as &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/create-project/&#34;&gt;described here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New git repository is created if:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you are creating a quickstart via &lt;code&gt;jx project quickstart&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you are running &lt;code&gt;jx project import&lt;/code&gt; inside a directory which has never been pushed to a git repository before&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Pull Request is created on your cluster repo that registers your app&amp;rsquo;s repository to the cluster
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this Pull Request will create or modify a file called &lt;code&gt;.jx/gitops/source-config.yaml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;jx project&lt;/code&gt; command now waits for:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the Pull Request to merge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lighthouse configuration to be updated to include the new repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a webhook to be setup for the new repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Pull Request on your cluster repo triggers a pipeline like the above &lt;a href=&#34;#promotion&#34;&gt;Promotion flow&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a second git commit is generated and pushed to the Pull Request with the title &lt;code&gt;chore: regenerated&lt;/code&gt; to add the git repository to the Lighthouse configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the Pull Request merges the above &lt;a href=&#34;#apply-step&#34;&gt;Apply step&lt;/a&gt; runs
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lighthouse configuration is updated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a Webhook is registered for Lighthouse on the app&amp;rsquo;s repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;jx project&lt;/code&gt; command now continues and pushes the new &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/pipelines/&#34;&gt;tekton pipelines for your app&lt;/a&gt; to the main branch of the git repository
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this triggers a new pipeline to run on your app which creates a new release of your app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;once the release is complete a Pull Request is created to start the &lt;a href=&#34;#promotion&#34;&gt;Promotion flow&lt;/a&gt; of the new app version&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when this Promote Pull Request merges your application will be running in &lt;code&gt;Staging&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see an example of this in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/blog/2020/09/16/jx-v3-alpha/&#34;&gt;demo of Jenkins X V3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;secrets&#34;&gt;Secrets&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/faq/general/#why-does-jenkins-x-use-helmfile-template&#34;&gt;check all of the kubernetes resources into git&lt;/a&gt; so they are all nicely versioned through time so its easy to diagnose when things start to misbehave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we do this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any &lt;strong&gt;Secret&lt;/strong&gt; resource generated in a helm chart is is converted to an &lt;strong&gt;ExternalSecret&lt;/strong&gt; so that it can be checked into git
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx-secret#mappings&#34;&gt;secret mapping&lt;/a&gt; to generate &lt;strong&gt;ExternalSecret&lt;/strong&gt; resources which define where the &lt;code&gt;Secret&lt;/code&gt; will be populated from (e.g. vault or your cloud provider secret store)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;secrets can be populated by either:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;directly in the secret store (e.g. via vault or the cloud secret store directly). If you are using vault you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/guides/secrets/vault/#using-vault&#34;&gt;follow these instructions&lt;/a&gt; to access the vault UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/guides/secrets/#edit-secrets&#34;&gt;jx secret edit&lt;/a&gt; command&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/reference/jx/secret/populate&#34;&gt;jx secret populate&lt;/a&gt; command inside the boot job which uses the &lt;code&gt;versionStream/charts/*/secret-schema.yaml&lt;/code&gt; files to populate with generators and default values from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx-secret#schema&#34;&gt;secret schema files&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What this basically means is that helm charts with secrets just work and you can then modify secrets or rotate secrets via the secret store. Also if you lose or move a cluster, GitOps will restore your cluster again using the contents of your git repository and whatever is in your secret store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;troubleshooting&#34;&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are not able to create quickstarts or import projects its most probably webhooks not being setup correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/admin/troubleshooting/webhooks/&#34;&gt;webhooks troubleshooting guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;comparison-to-2x&#34;&gt;Comparison to 2.x&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a high level Jenkins X 3.x similar to 2.x in that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We use GitOps to manage applications, configurations and versions; keeping everything but secret values in git&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However we’ve made a few changes in 3.x:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/admin/platform/&#34;&gt;simpler UX now for setting up Jenkins X&lt;/a&gt; which uses a library of GitOps repository templates you can start from
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This lets you choose the closest example to the kind of infrastructure, tools and secret store you want to use so it’s easier to get started if your requirements fit the common quickstarts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The setup/install/upgrade process runs inside kubernetes rather than on a developers laptop
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This avoids all kinds of issues with different installations of tools like git, kubectl, helm etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In 2.x we always had a git repository for Dev, Staging and Production. In 3.x if those environments are all inside the same cluster we use the same git repository for configuring cluster level resources and resources in any namespaces.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So by default there is 1 git repository with Jenkins X 3.x for the installation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whenever you create separate clusters (e.g. for muticluster support and you want Staging / Production environments to be separate), then each cluster gets its own git repository.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>V3: Extending</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/v3/about/extending/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/v3/about/extending/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Jenkins X has a number of extension points you can use to extend the CI/CD platform to suit your needs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;charts&#34;&gt;Charts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://helm.sh/&#34;&gt;Helm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://helm.sh/docs/topics/charts/&#34;&gt;charts&lt;/a&gt; are the standard way to package applications for kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to use GitOps to &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/apps/#adding-charts&#34;&gt;add charts&lt;/a&gt; to any of your clusters and &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/apps/#customising-charts&#34;&gt;customize them&lt;/a&gt; however you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also easily &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/apps/#adding-resources&#34;&gt;add one or more kubernetes resources to a cluster via a source layout chart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plugins&#34;&gt;Plugins&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;jx&lt;/code&gt; command line in version 3 is build on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx#plugins&#34;&gt;plugins&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out anyone can create a new plugin to wrap up some functionality that is either ran on a developer laptop or is used via a container image inside a pipeline step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plugins usually written in &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; as it has awesome Kubernetes support and generates easy to use statically compiled binaries - though you are free to create plugins in any programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you wish to create a new plugin try browse the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x-plugins&#34;&gt;jenkins-x-plugins organisation&lt;/a&gt; for inspiration or check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx#plugins&#34;&gt;standard plugins used in the jx cli&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;developing-plugins&#34;&gt;Developing Plugins&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to work on the plugins is to clone the source of a plugin locally and make local changes and build the code (you will need a &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/doc/install&#34;&gt;go 1.15 installation&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;e.g.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;git clone https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx-gitops 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;cd jx-gitops
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;make build
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now you can test out the local build of a plugin by calling &lt;strong&gt;./build/jx-gitops&lt;/strong&gt; instead of using, say &lt;strong&gt;jx gitops&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;testing-local-builds-with-jx&#34;&gt;Testing local builds with &lt;strong&gt;jx&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you add your &lt;strong&gt;./build&lt;/strong&gt; for your locally built plugin to your &lt;strong&gt;$PATH&lt;/strong&gt; environment variable you can invoke your local &lt;strong&gt;./build/jx-gitops&lt;/strong&gt; binary as if its a regular &lt;strong&gt;jx&lt;/strong&gt; plugin via:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;jx gitops help
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Basically &lt;strong&gt;jx myplugin&lt;/strong&gt; will normally download the &lt;strong&gt;jx-myplugin&lt;/strong&gt; binary and invoke that - unless it finds &lt;strong&gt;jx-myplugin&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;strong&gt;$PATH&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;using-a-specific-version-of-a-plugin&#34;&gt;Using a specific version of a plugin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to test a new plugin version before its been tested released in the version stream you can use an environment variable&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;export JX_GITOPS_VERSION 1.2.3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# we will now try version 1.2.3 of the gitops plugin:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;jx gitops help
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;triggers&#34;&gt;Triggers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With version 3.x we default to using &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/pipelines/&#34;&gt;Pipeline Catalogs&lt;/a&gt; containing Tekton resources to define CI/CD pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;e.g. the default CI/CD pipelines from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx3-pipeline-catalog/tree/master/packs&#34;&gt;default Jenkins X Pipeline Catalog&lt;/a&gt; define tekton pipelines in the &lt;code&gt;.lighthouse/jenkins-x&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside each repository there is now a trigger file called &lt;code&gt;triggers.yaml&lt;/code&gt; defined at&lt;code&gt;.lighthouse/jenkins-x/triggers.yaml&lt;/code&gt; to define the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/lighthouse&#34;&gt;lighthouse&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;presubmits&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;postsubmits&lt;/code&gt; (i.e. Pull Request pipelines and release pipelines).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can add any number of folders with the &lt;code&gt;.lighthouse&lt;/code&gt; folder to add any number of &lt;code&gt;presubmits&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;postsubmits&lt;/code&gt; (i.e. Pull Request pipelines and releases).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you define a pipeline you want to share with other repositories you can then use &lt;a href=&#34;https://googlecontainertools.github.io/kpt/reference/pkg/get/&#34;&gt;kpt pkg get&lt;/a&gt; to copy the folder into other repositories. Later on you can then use &lt;a href=&#34;https://googlecontainertools.github.io/kpt/reference/pkg/update/&#34;&gt;kpt pkg update&lt;/a&gt; to replicate upstream changes to other repositories. Or use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/guides/upgrade/#cluster&#34;&gt;jx gitops upgrade&lt;/a&gt; command which uses &lt;code&gt;kpt pkg update&lt;/code&gt; under the covers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pipeline-catalog&#34;&gt;Pipeline Catalog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;pipeline catalog&lt;/code&gt; contains default triggers, tekton pipelines and associated files (e.g. &lt;code&gt;Dockerfile&lt;/code&gt; and helm charts) for different languages and runtimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pipeline catalog is used to default the triggers, pipelines and other files for &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/create-project/&#34;&gt;new projects&lt;/a&gt; when you import or create new quickstarts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can browse the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx3-pipeline-catalog/tree/master/packs&#34;&gt;default Jenkins X Pipeline Catalog here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want you can fork the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx3-pipeline-catalog&#34;&gt;jenkins-x/jx3-pipeline-catalog&lt;/a&gt; repository and make your modifications to add/remove folders for different languages or modify the pipelines and associated files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;d prefer if any improvements or enhancements could be submitted back to the project via a Pull Request then we all get to share your improvements; but its totally fine to have some local modifications for your specific business requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To use your custom fork modify the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jx3-gitops-repositories/jx3-kubernetes/blob/master/extensions/pipeline-catalog.yaml&#34;&gt;extensions/pipeline-catalog.yaml&lt;/a&gt; file in your cluster git repository to link to your fork instead of the  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx3-pipeline-catalog&#34;&gt;jenkins-x/jx3-pipeline-catalog&lt;/a&gt; repository:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34; data-lang=&#34;yaml&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;...
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;apiVersion&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;project.jenkins-x.io/v1alpha1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;kind&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;PipelineCatalog&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;metadata&lt;/span&gt;:
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;creationTimestamp&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;spec&lt;/span&gt;:
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;repositories&lt;/span&gt;:
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  - &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;gitRef&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0ad0e49dca4d3a1e952c6f7c548e77b2136c5035&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;gitUrl&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;https://github.com/myorg/jx3-pipeline-catalog&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;label&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;My Pipeline Catalog&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;updatebot-for-custom-pipeline-catalogs&#34;&gt;Updatebot for custom pipeline catalogs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use &lt;em&gt;updatebot&lt;/em&gt; to keep your custom pipeline catalog up to date. Add this config to your cluster repo in &lt;em&gt;.jx/updatebot.yaml&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34; data-lang=&#34;yaml&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;apiVersion&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;updatebot.jenkins-x.io/v1alpha1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;kind&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;UpdateConfig&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;spec&lt;/span&gt;:
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;rules&lt;/span&gt;:
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    - &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;urls&lt;/span&gt;:
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;        - &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;https://github.com/my-org/jx3-pipeline-catalog&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;changes&lt;/span&gt;:
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;        - &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;regex&lt;/span&gt;:
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;pattern&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;jenkins-x/jx:(.*)&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;files&lt;/span&gt;:
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;              - &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;**/*.yaml&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;        - &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;regex&lt;/span&gt;:
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;pattern&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;jenkins-x/jx-boot:(.*)&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;files&lt;/span&gt;:
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;              - &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;**/*.yaml&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;To update your pipeline catalog with every cluster upgrade, add these steps to your &lt;em&gt;.lighthouse/jenkins-x/release.yaml&lt;/em&gt;  before the &lt;em&gt;admin-log&lt;/em&gt; step:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34; data-lang=&#34;yaml&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;- &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;image&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;perl:slim&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;next-version&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;script&lt;/span&gt;: |&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;    #!/usr/bin/env sh
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;    perl -ne&amp;#39;/version: (.*)/ &amp;amp;&amp;amp; print $1&amp;#39; versionStream/packages/jx.yml &amp;gt; VERSION&lt;/span&gt;    
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;- &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;image&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;uses:jenkins-x/jx3-pipeline-catalog/tasks/updatebot/release.yaml@versionStream&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;promote-release&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This will open a PR on the pipeline catalog repo if updates are available. If Jenkins X manages the pipeline catalog repo, the PRs will be automatically merged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;quickstarts&#34;&gt;QuickStarts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quickstarts are sample projects which are used &lt;code&gt;jx project quickstart&lt;/code&gt; when you &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/create-project/&#34;&gt;create new projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default quickstart projects are in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x-quickstarts/&#34;&gt;jenkins-x-quickstarts&lt;/a&gt; github organisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quickstarts are defined in your &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jx3-gitops-repositories/jx3-kubernetes/blob/master/extensions/quickstarts.yaml&#34;&gt;extensions/quickstarts.yaml&lt;/a&gt; file and defaults to including all of the quickstarts in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jx3-gitops-repositories/jx3-kubernetes/blob/master/versionStream/quickstarts.yaml&#34;&gt;versionStream/quickstarts.yml&lt;/a&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can include/exclude quickstarts from the version stream using the &lt;code&gt;includes&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;excludes&lt;/code&gt; regular expressions in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jx3-gitops-repositories/jx3-kubernetes/blob/master/extensions/quickstarts.yaml&#34;&gt;extensions/quickstarts.yaml&lt;/a&gt; file as shown below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can add your own quickstarts into the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jx3-gitops-repositories/jx3-kubernetes/blob/master/extensions/quickstarts.yaml&#34;&gt;extensions/quickstarts.yaml&lt;/a&gt; file as follows&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34; data-lang=&#34;yaml&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;apiVersion&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;project.jenkins-x.io/v1alpha1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;kind&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;Quickstarts&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;spec&lt;/span&gt;:
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;defaultOwner&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;myorg&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# custom quickstarts&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;quickstarts&lt;/span&gt;:
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  - &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;cheese&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;language&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;downloadZipURL&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;https://codeload.github.com/jenkins-x-quickstarts/cheese/zip/master&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# shared quickstarts from the version stream&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;imports&lt;/span&gt;:
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  - &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;file&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;versionStream/quickstarts.yaml&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;includes&lt;/span&gt;:
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    - &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;.*&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;excludes&lt;/span&gt;:
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    - &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;.*/node.*&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;octant&#34;&gt;Octant&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our preferred UI for Kubernetes, Tekton and Jenkins X is &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/v3/develop/ui/octant&#34;&gt;octant&lt;/a&gt; as its easy to install/run and has fined grained RBAC and security without the hassle of setting up TLS, DNS and SSO on every cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the awesome features of &lt;a href=&#34;https://octant.dev/&#34;&gt;Octant&lt;/a&gt; is it supports plugins so that anyone can build a plugin to extend the UI. We&amp;rsquo;ve created the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/octant-jx&#34;&gt;octant-jx&lt;/a&gt; plugin to extend &lt;a href=&#34;https://octant.dev/&#34;&gt;Octant&lt;/a&gt; with the Jenkins X capabilities of environments, pipelines, source repositories and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you wish to extend &lt;a href=&#34;https://octant.dev/&#34;&gt;Octant&lt;/a&gt; further either contribute to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkins-x/octant-jx&#34;&gt;octant-jx&lt;/a&gt; plugin or create your own!&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
