<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Get Started on Jenkins X</title>
    <link>http://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Get Started on Jenkins X</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Get jx</title>
      <link>http://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/install/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/install/</guid>
      <description>Pick the most suitable instructions for your operating system:
macOs On a Mac you can use brew:
brew tap jenkins-x/jx brew install jx  Or if you have not installed brew and prefer to install by hand:
curl -L https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx/releases/download/v1.2.16/jx-darwin-amd64.tar.gz | tar xzv sudo mv jx /usr/local/bin Linux curl -L https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx/releases/download/v1.2.16/jx-linux-amd64.tar.gz | tar xzv sudo mv jx /usr/local/bin Other platforms download the binary for jx and add it to your $PATH</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create new Cluster</title>
      <link>http://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/create-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/create-cluster/</guid>
      <description>To create a new Kubernetes cluster with Jenkins X installed use the jx create cluster command.
A number of different public cloud providers are supported as shown below.
For the best getting started experience we currently recommend using Google Container Engine (GKE). The Google Cloud Platform offers a $300 free credit if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a Google Cloud account. See https://console.cloud.google.com/freetrial
Here&amp;rsquo;s a little demo showing GKE, AKS and Minikube in parallel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install on Kubernetes</title>
      <link>http://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/install-on-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/install-on-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Jenkins X can be installed on 1.8 or later of Kubernetes. The requirements are:
 RBAC is enabled insecure docker registries are enabled. This is so that pipelines can use a docker registry running inside the kubernetes cluster (which typically is not public so no https support). You can modify your pipelines to use other registries later.  Enabling insecure registries on kops Note that if you are on AWS you may want to use the jx create aws command which automates all of this for you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s next?</title>
      <link>http://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/next/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/next/</guid>
      <description>OK so you have got the jx CLI and you either
 created a Kubernetes cluster with Jenkins X installed Jenkins X on an existing kubernetes cluster  So whats next?
Well the Developing section contains the next steps you may want to try out, such as
 create a new Spring Boot application and import it into Jenkins X create a new quickstart and import it into Jenkins X import existing source code into Jenkins X browsing for browsing pipelines, builds, apps and activity  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>