<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Get Started on Jenkins X</title>
    <link>https://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Get Started on Jenkins X</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Get jx</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/install/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/install/</guid>
      <description>Pick the most suitable instructions for your operating system:
macOS On a Mac you can use brew:
brew tap jenkins-x/jx brew install jx  Or if you have not installed brew and prefer to install by hand:
curl -L https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx/releases/download/v2.0.239/jx-darwin-amd64.tar.gz | tar xzv sudo mv jx /usr/local/bin Linux mkdir -p ~/.jx/bin curl -L https://github.com/jenkins-x/jx/releases/download/v2.0.239/jx-linux-amd64.tar.gz | tar xzv -C ~/.jx/bin export PATH=$PATH:~/.jx/bin echo &amp;#39;export PATH=$PATH:~/.jx/bin&amp;#39; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ~/.bashrc Windows  If you use Chocolatey, then there is a package available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create new Cluster</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/create-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/create-cluster/</guid>
      <description>To create a new Kubernetes cluster with Jenkins X installed use the jx create cluster command.
A number of different public cloud providers are supported as shown below.
For the best getting started experience we currently recommend using Google Container Engine (GKE). The Google Cloud Platform offers a $300 free credit if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a Google Cloud account. See https://console.cloud.google.com/freetrial
Here&amp;rsquo;s a little demo showing GKE, AKS and Minikube in parallel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install on Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/install-on-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/install-on-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Jenkins X can be installed on 1.8 or later of Kubernetes. The requirements are:
 RBAC is enabled Your Kubernetes cluster has a default storage class setup so that Persistent Volume Claims can be bound to Persistent Volumes If not using the aws or eks providers, then we need to make sure that insecure Docker registries are enabled. This is so that pipelines can use a Docker registry running inside the Kubernetes cluster (which typically is not public, so no https support).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What happens during installation</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/install-on-cluster-what-happens/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/install-on-cluster-what-happens/</guid>
      <description>The Jenkins X CLI will do the following when installing the Jenkins X platform:
Install client binaries to manage your cluster  If you are running on Mac OS X, Jenkins X is using Homebrew to install the various CLI. It will install it if not present.
  Install kubectl kubectl is the CLI of Kubernetes. It allows you to interact with your Kubernetes cluster via the API server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage by GitOps</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/manage-via-gitops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/manage-via-gitops/</guid>
      <description>We recommend you use GitOps to manage your installation of Jenkins X, to upgrade it, configure it and add or remove extension Apps so it’s easy to audit who changes what in your installation and to easily revert bad changes.
Currently this only works on AWS and Google cloud as it requires our vault operator (which needs cloud storage &amp;amp; KMS) to store secrets while all other configuration is stored in the development environment git repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Clusters</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/multi-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/multi-cluster/</guid>
      <description>A common requirement for a production setup is to isolate your Development, Staging and Production environments onto separate kubernetes clusters and to isolate the clusters from each other in separate cloud accounts or VPNs etc.
You can do this by installing the Environment Controller chart into your Staging or Production cluster.
Goal Our assumption with the Environment Controller is that we need something that:
 runs inside your Staging or Production cluster to avoid having to expose write/admin access to Staging/Production outside of your cluster has a small with minimal RBAC footprint so it can be installed in any namespace in any Staging/Production cluster which are usually really locked down for security makes few assumptions about the cluster (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s next?</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/next/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/next/</guid>
      <description>OK so you have got the jx CLI and you either
 created a Kubernetes cluster with Jenkins X installed Jenkins X on an existing kubernetes cluster  So whats next?
Well the Developing section contains the next steps you may want to try out, such as
 create a new Spring Boot application and import it into Jenkins X create a new quickstart and import it into Jenkins X import existing source code into Jenkins X browsing for browsing pipelines, builds, apps and activity  You may also want to check out the various demonstrations of what you can do with Jenkins X</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/config/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/config/</guid>
      <description>Jenkins X should work out of the box with smart defaults for your cloud provider. e.g. Jenkins X automatically uses ECR if you are using AWS or EKS.
However you can configure values in the underlying helm charts used by Jenkins X.
To do this you need to create a myvalues.yaml file in the current directory you are in when you run either jx create cluster or jx install</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create custom Builder</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/create-custom-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/create-custom-builder/</guid>
      <description>In Jenkins X, it is possible to create your custom Builders (aka POD templates) or overwrite existing onces. You just need to base your Docker image on this builder-base image or on its slim version. These images contain a number of pre-installed tools which get constantly updated and published to Docker Hub.
Create a custom Builder from scratch Builder image First you need to create a docker image for your builder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create EKS cluster on AWS</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/aws-terraform-install-gitops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/aws-terraform-install-gitops/</guid>
      <description>This is a short guide to setup EKS on AWS and the required resources for Jenkins X&amp;rsquo;s setup of Vault using Terraform. It assumes access to AWS is configured and familiarity with AWS, kubectl and Terraform.
This snippet of Terraform code sets EKS and up needed resources on AWS. It outputs the parameters you then need to add to append to jx install.
eks.tf   variable &amp;#34;region&amp;#34; { } variable &amp;#34;subnets&amp;#34; { type = &amp;#34;list&amp;#34; } variable &amp;#34;vpc_id&amp;#34; { } variable &amp;#34;key_name&amp;#34; { description = &amp;#34;SSH key name for worker nodes&amp;#34; } variable &amp;#34;bucket_domain&amp;#34; { description = &amp;#34;Suffix for S3 bucket used for vault unseal operation&amp;#34; } provider &amp;#34;aws&amp;#34; { region = &amp;#34;${var.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Jenkins X on GKE Properly</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/jenkins-x-gke-install-with-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 07:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/getting-started/jenkins-x-gke-install-with-bot/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: This tutorial is based on the following jx version
NAME VERSION jx 2.0.33 jenkins x platform 2.0.108 Kubernetes cluster v1.11.8-gke.6 kubectl v1.14.0 helm client Client: v2.13.1+g618447c git git version 2.21.0 Operating System Mac OS X 10.14.3 build 18D42    Overview In this tutorial, we walk you through a full setup of Jenkinx X in GKE, including setup of the Bot. We will install Jenkins X Serverless topology which also brings Tekton pipelines for us to use in this scenario.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>