<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jenkins X News on Jenkins X</title>
    <link>https://jenkins-x.io/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jenkins X News on Jenkins X</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 11:27:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jenkins-x.io/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Jenkins X on Alibaba Cloud Container Service</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/news/alibaba-container-service-jenkins-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 07:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/news/alibaba-container-service-jenkins-x/</guid>
      <description>Installing Jenkins X on Alibaba Cloud Container Service   Installing Jenkins X in Alibaba Kubernetes Container Service Jenkins X has just added initial support to install in Alibaba Container Service, its Kubernetes offering.
The following instructions allow installation in a managed Kubernetes cluster in any region outside of mainland China, where more configuration is needed avoid using Google services blocked by chinese authorities (Helm charts and Docker images in GCR).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevOps World-Jenkins World 2019 San Francisco: Agenda is Live</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/news/jenkins-world-agenda/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 12:20:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/news/jenkins-world-agenda/</guid>
      <description>DevOps World | Jenkins World is the largest Jenkins gathering of the year. From August 12 - 15, 2019 the event will take place at the Moscone West Center in San Francisco. The event boasts 100+ sessions, and will offer training, hands-on workshops, onsite certification, contributor summit and much more. Conference attendees can expect to be inspired while learning the latest innovations from industry leaders. Attendees will learn the value that digital transformation has in delivering software more efficiently, more quickly and with higher quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins Community Awards</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/news/jenkins-community-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 12:20:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/news/jenkins-community-awards/</guid>
      <description>It is time for the 3rd annual, DevOps World | Jenkins World 2019 Community Awards. These nominations are indicative of the excellent work Jenkins community members are doing for the betterment of Jenkins.
This will be the third year we are commemorating community members who have shown excellence through commitment, creative thinking, and contributions to continue making Jenkins a great open source community.
The award categories include:  Most Valuable Contributor - This award is presented to the Jenkins contributor who has helped move the Jenkins project forward the most through their invaluable feature contributions, bug fixes or plugin development efforts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Jenkins X Kubernetes Clusters Using Infrastructure as Code With Terraform</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/news/terraform-jenkins-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 07:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/news/terraform-jenkins-x/</guid>
      <description>Provision Jenkins X Kubernetes Clusters using Terraform    CAUTION: Do not make updates to the cluster that require recreating the cluster resources, all data will be lost. Only changes that update the cluster are supported at this time.
  Overview Many organizations have adopted DevOps practices in the last few years. This is valuable as it relates to Jenkins X as we provide a way to manage the Kubernetes clusters Infrastructure as Code which is one of the core concepts of DevOps practices as it relates to automation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins X joins the CDF</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/news/jenkins-x-cdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 07:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/news/jenkins-x-cdf/</guid>
      <description>We are thrilled to announce that Jenkins X will be joining the Continuous Delivery Foundation as one of the founding projects. The Continuous Delivery Foundation (CDF) is a brand new sub-foundation of the Linux Foundation and will be dedicated to advancing the practice of continuous delivery and nurturing an ecosystem of interoperable tools for software delivery.
Jenkins X is just over a year old but has been growing rapidly as the CI/CD solution for modern cloud applications on Kubernetes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins X Pipelines integrated with Tekton</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/news/jenkins-x-next-gen-pipeline-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 10:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/news/jenkins-x-next-gen-pipeline-engine/</guid>
      <description>Introducing the new Jenkins X Pipeline Engine The Jenkins X team and CloudBees are excited to announce some changes that we’ve been working on and are jntroducing the new Jenkins X Pipeline Engine.
  Today, there are two ways that you can run your Jenkins pipelines in Jenkins X.
By default today, Jenkins X uses a static traditional Jenkins master and Jenkins Pipelines. This mode works well for those who may have complex existing Jenkins pipelines and want to be able to use all the Jenkins X goodness of GitOps and preview environments in Kubernetes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy 1st Birthday Jenkins X</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/news/happy-first-birthday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 07:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/news/happy-first-birthday/</guid>
      <description>Time flies when you are delivering software. It has been just over a year since the initial commit went into Github for Jenkins X, the CI/CD solution for cloud native. In just 12 months, Jenkins X progress has been breathtaking, so let’s celebrate by taking a look at all that has been accomplished in this short space of time.
One of the main founders of Jenkins X is James Strachan of CloudBees, who is known for building many popular open source software projects such as Apache Groovy, Apache Camel and fabric8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Jenkins X Mas!</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/news/changes-20-december-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 15:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/news/changes-20-december-2018/</guid>
      <description>As we head towards the holiday season I wanted to call out some recent events in the Jenkins X community. Its been an amazing year and we&amp;rsquo;re looking forward to celebrating Jenkins X birthday in January!
Webinar on Serverless Jenkins and Jenkins X Yesterday James Strachan and James Rawlings gave a webinar on Servlerless Jenkins with Jenkins X. You should be able to watch the recording (registration required).
We had hundreds of folks who asked some really great questions - thanks to all those who attended!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here comes Cloud Native Jenkins</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/news/changes-november-26-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 08:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/news/changes-november-26-2018/</guid>
      <description>The last few months have been crazy busy in the Jenkins X community. We&amp;rsquo;ve had 2 Jenkins World conferences in San Francisco and Nice, introduced serverless jenkins and tiller-less helm
Now we have released support for Cloud Native Jenkins which lets us support pluggable workloads for different teams (e.g. kubernetes workloads, traditional workloads of libraries and binaries or other workloads).
For more details on Cloud Native Jenkins please see the Cloud Native Jenkins documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serverless Jenkins</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/news/serverless-jenkins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 07:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/news/serverless-jenkins/</guid>
      <description> Serverless Jenkins James Rawlings has just published an excellent article on Serverless Jenkins with Jenkins X that is well worth a read.
It describes how you can use it via the --prow feature flag when using either jx create cluster
jx create cluster gke --prow  or jx install
jx install --prow  For more details see the blog or check out the video:
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helm 2.x without Tiller</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/news/helm-without-tiller/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 07:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/news/helm-without-tiller/</guid>
      <description>How to avoid Tiller Helm 2.x uses a server side component called tiller. Typically Tiller is installed in a global namespace; or you can install a Tiller in each namespace and configure your helm CLI to talk to the right tiller in the right namespace.
However Tiller has a number of issues&amp;hellip;
The problem with Tiller  complicates RBAC since its not using the RBAC of the user or pod running the helm commands to read/write kubernetes resources - helm is talking to the remote tiller pod to do the work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins X at Jenkins World</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/news/jenkins-x-at-jenkinsworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 08:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/news/jenkins-x-at-jenkinsworld/</guid>
      <description>Jenkins X at JenkinsWorld Jenkins World has combined with DevOps world to become the premier DevOps event in your calendar this year - and there really isn&amp;rsquo;t much time left if you still have to register. The event is happening at San Francisco 16-19 September, and Nice,France 22-25 October. To get a discount on entry - you are invited to use the dscount code: JWRDAVIES
Some of the Jenkins X team, including James Strachan, James Rawlings, Rob Davies and Pete Muir will be available if you want some extra help with the Jenkins X project - we are cheap too - beer tokens gratefully received.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes for August 24 2018</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/news/changes-august-24-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 16:55:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/news/changes-august-24-2018/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve had a crazy busy summer on the Jenkins X Project. We&amp;rsquo;ve been so busy we&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten to even blog about it ;)
Before we go over whats happened - a big thanks to all of our new committers and contributors listed below.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick summary of some of the main things that&amp;rsquo;s happened this summer:
 we have awesome new tutorials to get you started even faster on GKE we now have full support AWS both kops and EKS with ECR support OOTB thanks to the excellent eksctl tool which helps us create EKS clusters on Amazon Gareth wrote an awesome blog describing how we can auomate spinning up a CodeShip CI job that automates your cloud infrastructure, setting up 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes for May 21 2018</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/news/changes-may-21-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 14:35:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/news/changes-may-21-2018/</guid>
      <description>Its been a busy 24 days since our last blog post.
We had our first Jenkins X Office Hours which was lots of fun. We meet every other Thursday at 5pm BST / 12pm US Eastern. Feel free to add your questions to the doc or hangout live and ask questions in person. More details on the community page.
We also did a bunch of presentations:
 James Strachan presented Jenkins X at DevOxx UK with a live demo on GKE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins X does KubeCon</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/news/jenkins-x-does-kubecon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 10:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/news/jenkins-x-does-kubecon/</guid>
      <description>Jenkins X at KubeCon Here is the video of my talk: Jenkins X: Easy CI/CD for Kubernetes at KubeCon Europe 2018.
 You can also get the slides from this talk here
You can also watch all the other KubeCon videos here
You can also register your interest in the CloudBees Kubernetes product that I gave a quick sneak peek at towards the end of the talk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes for April 27 2018</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/news/changes-april-27-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 15:30:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/news/changes-april-27-2018/</guid>
      <description>Changes for April 27 2018 Its 16 days since our last blog post and we&amp;rsquo;ve been really busy again!
Here&amp;rsquo;s some of the main highlights:
 we have moved to using skaffold for building docker images so that we can easily take advantage of things like Google Container Builder or kaniko new DevPods are a thing; making it easy to use your kubernetes cluster for building, testing and running apps new integration with Anchore for security scanning via jx get cve or in a pipeline you can use jx step post build - we&amp;rsquo;ll blog separately about that next week thanks to the work of @LinuxSuRen we now have the initial Chinese translation of the Jenkins X documentation we now support MiniShift as well as AKS, AWS, GKE and vanilla kubernetes clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes for April 11 2018</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/news/changes-april-11-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 16:33:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/news/changes-april-11-2018/</guid>
      <description>Changes for April 11 2018 We announced Jenkins X a mere 23 days ago and the feedback has been truly humbling. Thank you all for the awesome feedback!
We&amp;rsquo;ve made a lot of progress and improvements! The rest of the blog goes into more detail.
But first I&amp;rsquo;d like to call out a few specific details from the Jenkins X Futures:
 we now fully support GitHub and GitHub enterprise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Jenkins X</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/news/introducing-jenkins-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 18:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/news/introducing-jenkins-x/</guid>
      <description>Introducing Jenkins X There&amp;rsquo;s a new blog post on jenkins.io which introduces Jenkins X and gives an overview of what it, what we&amp;rsquo;re doing and why:
 Introducing Jenkins X: a CI/CD solution for modern cloud applications on Kubernetes  Please check it out and let us know what you think</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JEP 400 submitted</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/news/jep-400-submitted/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 18:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/news/jep-400-submitted/</guid>
      <description>JEP 400 Submitted for Jenkins X We have submitted JEP 400 to propose Jenkins X as a sub project in the Jenkins Foundation.
Please check out JEP 400 and let us know what you think on the Jenkins dev list.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>