<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Commands on Jenkins X</title>
    <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Commands on Jenkins X</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jenkins-x.io/commands/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>jx</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx/</guid>
      <description> jx jx is a command line tool for working with Jenkins X
Synopsis jx  SEE ALSO  jx cdx - Opens the CDX dashboard for visualising CI / CD and your environments jx completion - Output shell completion code for the given shell (bash or zsh) jx console - Opens the Jenkins console jx context - View or change the current kubernetes context (kubernetes cluster) jx create - Create a new resource jx delete - Deletes one or many resources jx edit - Edit a resource jx environment - View or change the current environment in the current kubernetes cluster jx get - Display one or many resources jx import - Imports a local project or git repository into Jenkins jx init - Init Jenkins X jx install - Install Jenkins X in the current Kubernetes cluster jx logs - Tails the log of the latest pod for a deployment jx namespace - View or change the current namespace context in the current kubernetes cluster jx open - Open a service in a browser jx preview - Creates or updates a Preview Environment for the current version of an application jx promote - Promotes a version of an application to an environment jx prompt - Generate the command line prompt for the current team and environment jx rsh - Opens a terminal in a pod or runs a command in the pod jx shell - Create a sub shell so that changes to the kubernetes context, namespace or environment remain local to the shell jx start - Starts a process such as a pipeline jx step - pipeline steps jx uninstall - Uninstall the Jenkins X platform jx upgrade - Upgrades a resource jx version - Print the version information  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx cdx</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_cdx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_cdx/</guid>
      <description> jx cdx Opens the CDX dashboard for visualising CI / CD and your environments
Synopsis Opens the CDX dashboard in a browser.
Which helps you visualise your CI / CD pipelines, apps, environments and teams.
jx cdx  Examples  # Open the CDX dashboard in a browser jx cdx # Print the Jenkins X console URL but do not open a browser jx console -u  Options  -u, --url Only displays and the URL and does not open the browser  SEE ALSO  jx - jx is a command line tool for working with Jenkins X  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx completion</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_completion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_completion/</guid>
      <description>jx completion Output shell completion code for the given shell (bash or zsh)
Synopsis Output shell completion code for the given shell (bash or zsh).
This command prints shell code which must be evaluation to provide interactive completion of jx commands.
$ source &amp;lt;(jx completion bash)
will load the jx completion code for bash. Note that this depends on the bash-completion framework. It must be sourced before sourcing the jx completion, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx console</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_console/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_console/</guid>
      <description> jx console Opens the Jenkins console
Synopsis Opens the Jenkins X console in a browser.
jx console  Examples  # Open the Jenkins X console in a browser jx console # Print the Jenkins X console URL but do not open a browser jx console -u  Options  -e, --env string Specifies the Environment name to look inside -n, --namespace string Specifies the namespace name to look inside -u, --url Only displays and the URL and does not open the browser  SEE ALSO  jx - jx is a command line tool for working with Jenkins X  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx context</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_context/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_context/</guid>
      <description> jx context View or change the current kubernetes context (kubernetes cluster)
Synopsis Displays or changes the current kubernetes context (cluster).
jx context  Examples  # to select the context to switch to jx context # or the more concise alias jx ctx # view the current context jx ctx -b # Change the current namespace to &#39;minikube&#39; jx ctx minikube  Options  -b, --batch-mode In batch mode the command never prompts for user input --headless Enable headless operation if using browser automation --verbose Enable verbose logging  SEE ALSO  jx - jx is a command line tool for working with Jenkins X  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx create</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create/</guid>
      <description> jx create Create a new resource
Synopsis Creates a new resource.
Valid resource types include:
 archetype
 cluster
 env
 git
 spring (aka &amp;lsquo;springboot&amp;rsquo;)   jx create  SEE ALSO  jx - jx is a command line tool for working with Jenkins X jx create addon - Creates an addon jx create archetype - Create a new app from a Maven Archetype and import the generated code into git and Jenkins for CI / CD jx create cluster - Create a new kubernetes cluster jx create docs - Creates the documentation files jx create environment - Create a new Environment which is used to promote your Team&amp;rsquo;s Applications via Continuous Delivery jx create etc-hosts - Creates a new git server URL jx create git - Creates a git resource jx create issue - Create an issue on the git project for the current directory jx create jenkins - Creates a jenkins resource jx create spring - Create a new spring boot application and import the generated code into git and Jenkins for CI / CD  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx create addon</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_addon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_addon/</guid>
      <description> jx create addon Creates an addon
Synopsis Creates an addon
jx create addon  Options  --helm-update Should we run helm update first to ensure we use the latest version (default true) -n, --namespace string The Namespace to install into -r, --release string The chart release name (default &amp;quot;gitea&amp;quot;)  SEE ALSO  jx create - Create a new resource jx create addon cdx - Create the CDX addon (a web console for working with CI / CD and Environments) jx create addon gitea - Create a gitea addon for hosting git repositories  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx create addon cdx</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_addon_cdx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_addon_cdx/</guid>
      <description> jx create addon cdx Create the CDX addon (a web console for working with CI / CD and Environments)
Synopsis Creates the CDX addon
CDX provides unified Continuous Delivery Environment console to make it easier to do CI / CD and Environments across a number of microservices and teams
jx create addon cdx  Examples  # Create the cdx addon jx create addon cdx  Options  -b, --batch-mode In batch mode the command never prompts for user input --headless Enable headless operation if using browser automation --helm-update Should we run helm update first to ensure we use the latest version (default true) -n, --namespace string The Namespace to install into -r, --release string The chart release name (default &amp;quot;gitea&amp;quot;) --verbose Enable verbose logging  SEE ALSO  jx create addon - Creates an addon  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx create addon gitea</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_addon_gitea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_addon_gitea/</guid>
      <description>jx create addon gitea Create a gitea addon for hosting git repositories
Synopsis Creates the gitea addon (hosted git server)
jx create addon gitea  Examples  # Create the gitea addon jx create addon gitea  Options  --admin Should the new user created be an admin of the gitea server -b, --batch-mode In batch mode the command never prompts for user input -c, --chart string The name of the chart to use (default &amp;quot;jenkins-x/gitea&amp;quot;) -e, --email string The email address of the new user to create in gitea --headless Enable headless operation if using browser automation --helm-update Should we run helm update first to ensure we use the latest version (default true) -n, --namespace string The Namespace to install into --no-token If true disable trying to create a new token in the gitea server --no-user If true disable trying to create a new user in the gitea server -p, --password string The password for the user to create in gitea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx create archetype</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_archetype/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_archetype/</guid>
      <description>jx create archetype Create a new app from a Maven Archetype and import the generated code into git and Jenkins for CI / CD
Synopsis Creates a new Maven project using an Archetype
You then get the option to import the generated source code into a git repository and Jenkins for CI / CD
jx create archetype  Examples  # Create a new application from a Maven Archetype using the UI to choose which archetype to use jx create archetype # Creates a Camel Archetype, filtering on the archetypes containing the text &#39;spring&#39; jx create archetype -g org.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx create cluster</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_cluster/</guid>
      <description>jx create cluster Create a new kubernetes cluster
Synopsis This command creates a new kubernetes cluster, installing required local dependencies and provisions the Jenkins X platform
Valid kubernetes providers include:
* minikube (single-node Kubernetes cluster inside a VM on your laptop) * gke (Google Container Engine - https://cloud.google.com/kubernetes-engine) * aks (Azure Container Service - https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/aks) * coming soon: eks (Amazon Elastic Container Service - https://aws.amazon.com/eks)  Depending on which cloud provider your cluster is created on possible dependencies that will be installed are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx create cluster aks</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_cluster_aks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_cluster_aks/</guid>
      <description>jx create cluster aks Create a new kubernetes cluster on AKS: Runs on Azure
Synopsis This command creates a new kubernetes cluster on AKS, installing required local dependencies and provisions the Jenkins X platform
Azure Container Service (AKS) manages your hosted Kubernetes environment, making it quick and easy to deploy and manage containerized applications without container orchestration expertise. It also eliminates the burden of ongoing operations and maintenance by provisioning, upgrading, and scaling resources on demand, without taking your applications offline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx create cluster gke</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_cluster_gke/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_cluster_gke/</guid>
      <description>jx create cluster gke Create a new kubernetes cluster on GKE: Runs on Google Cloud
Synopsis This command creates a new kubernetes cluster on GKE, installing required local dependencies and provisions the Jenkins X platform
Google Kubernetes Engine is a managed environment for deploying containerized applications. It brings our latest innovations in developer productivity, resource efficiency, automated operations, and open source flexibility to accelerate your time to market.
Google has been running production workloads in containers for over 15 years, and we build the best of what we learn into Kubernetes, the industry-leading open source container orchestrator which powers Kubernetes Engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx create cluster minikube</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_cluster_minikube/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_cluster_minikube/</guid>
      <description>jx create cluster minikube Create a new kubernetes cluster with minikube: Runs locally
Synopsis This command creates a new kubernetes cluster, installing required local dependencies and provisions the Jenkins X platform
Minikube is a tool that makes it easy to run Kubernetes locally. Minikube runs a single-node Kubernetes cluster inside a VM on your laptop for users looking to try out Kubernetes or develop with it day-to-day.
jx create cluster minikube  Examples  jx create cluster minikube  Options  -b, --batch-mode In batch mode the command never prompts for user input --cleanup-temp-files Cleans up any temporary values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx create docs</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_docs/</guid>
      <description> jx create docs Creates the documentation files
Synopsis Creates the documentation markdown files
jx create docs  Examples  # Create the documentation files jx create docs  Options  -d, --dir string the directory to generate the docs into (default &amp;quot;.&amp;quot;)  SEE ALSO  jx create - Create a new resource  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx create environment</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_environment/</guid>
      <description>jx create environment Create a new Environment which is used to promote your Team&amp;rsquo;s Applications via Continuous Delivery
Synopsis Creates a new Environment An Environment maps to a kubernetes cluster and namespace and is a place that your team&amp;rsquo;s applications can be promoted to via Continous Delivery.
You can optionally use GitOps to manage the configuration of an Environment by storing all configuration in a git repository and then only changing it via Pull Requests and CI / CD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx create etc-hosts</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_etc-hosts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_etc-hosts/</guid>
      <description> jx create etc-hosts Creates a new git server URL
Synopsis Creates /etc/hosts entries for all current exposed services
jx create etc-hosts kind [url]  Examples  # Creates /etc/hosts entries for all current exposed services sudo jx create etc-hosts  Options  -i, --ip string The IP address of the node to point the host entries to -n, --name string The etc hosts file to edit (default &amp;quot;/etc/hosts&amp;quot;)  SEE ALSO  jx create - Create a new resource  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx create git</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_git/</guid>
      <description> jx create git Creates a git resource
Synopsis Creates a git resource
jx create git  SEE ALSO  jx create - Create a new resource jx create git server - Creates a new git server URL jx create git token - Adds a new API token for a user on a git server jx create git user - Adds a new user to the git server  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx create git server</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_git_server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_git_server/</guid>
      <description> jx create git server Creates a new git server URL
Synopsis Adds a new Git Server URL
jx create git server kind [url]  Examples  # Add a new git server URL jx create git server gitea  Options  -n, --name string The name for the git server being created  SEE ALSO  jx create git - Creates a git resource  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx create git token</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_git_token/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_git_token/</guid>
      <description> jx create git token Adds a new API token for a user on a git server
Synopsis Creates a new API Token for a user on a Git Server
jx create git token [username]  Examples  # Add a new API Token for a user for the local git server # prompting the user to find and enter the API Token jx create git token -n local someUserName # Add a new API Token for a user for the local git server # using browser automation to login to the git server # with the username an password to find the API Token jx create git token -n local -p somePassword someUserName  Options  -t, --api-token string The API Token for the user -b, --batch-mode In batch mode the command never prompts for user input --headless Enable headless operation if using browser automation -n, --name string The name of the git server to add a user -p, --password string The User password to try automatically create a new API Token --timeout string The timeout if using browser automation to generate the API token (by passing username and password) -u, --url string The URL of the git server to add a user --verbose Enable verbose logging  SEE ALSO  jx create git - Creates a git resource  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx create git user</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_git_user/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_git_user/</guid>
      <description> jx create git user Adds a new user to the git server
Synopsis Creates a new user for a Git Server. Only supported for Gitea so far
jx create git user [username]  Examples  # Creates a new user in the local gitea server jx create git user -n local someUserName -p somepassword -e foo@bar.com  Options  -a, --admin Whether the user is an admin user -t, --api-token string The API Token for the user -b, --batch-mode In batch mode the command never prompts for user input -e, --email string The User email address --headless Enable headless operation if using browser automation -n, --name string The name of the git server to add a user -p, --password string The User password to try automatically create a new API Token -u, --url string The URL of the git server to add a user --verbose Enable verbose logging  SEE ALSO  jx create git - Creates a git resource  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx create issue</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_issue/</guid>
      <description>jx create issue Create an issue on the git project for the current directory
Synopsis Creates an issue in a the git project of the current directory
jx create issue  Examples  # Create an issue in the current project jx create issue -t &amp;quot;something we should do&amp;quot; # Create an issue with a title and a body jx create issue -t &amp;quot;something we should do&amp;quot; --body &amp;quot; some more text goes here &amp;quot;&amp;quot; &amp;quot;  Options  -b, --batch-mode In batch mode the command never prompts for user input --body string The body of the issue --dir string The source directory used to detect the git repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx create jenkins</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_jenkins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_jenkins/</guid>
      <description> jx create jenkins Creates a jenkins resource
Synopsis Creates a jenkins resource
jx create jenkins  SEE ALSO  jx create - Create a new resource jx create jenkins token - Adds a new user name and api token for a Jenkins server  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx create jenkins token</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_jenkins_token/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_jenkins_token/</guid>
      <description> jx create jenkins token Adds a new user name and api token for a Jenkins server
Synopsis Creates a new user and API Token for the current Jenkins Server
jx create jenkins token [username]  Examples  # Add a new API Token for a user for the current Jenkins server # prompting the user to find and enter the API Token jx create jenkins token someUserName # Add a new API Token for a user for the current Jenkins server # using browser automation to login to the git server # with the username an password to find the API Token jx create jenkins token -p somePassword someUserName  Options  -t, --api-token string The API Token for the user -b, --batch-mode In batch mode the command never prompts for user input --headless Enable headless operation if using browser automation -n, --name string The name of the git server to add a user -p, --password string The User password to try automatically create a new API Token --timeout string The timeout if using browser automation to generate the API token (by passing username and password) -u, --url string The URL of the git server to add a user --verbose Enable verbose logging  SEE ALSO  jx create jenkins - Creates a jenkins resource  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx create spring</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_spring/</guid>
      <description>jx create spring Create a new spring boot application and import the generated code into git and Jenkins for CI / CD
Synopsis Creates a new Spring Boot application on the file system.
You then get the option to import the generated source code into a git repository and Jenkins for CI / CD
jx create spring  Examples  # Create a Spring Boot application where you use the terminal to pick the values jx create spring # Creates a Spring Boot application passing in the required dependencies jx create spring -d web -d actuator  Options  -x, --advanced Advanced mode can show more detailed forms for some resource kinds like springboot -a, --artifact string Artifact ID to generate -b, --batch-mode In batch mode the command never prompts for user input -t, --boot-version string Spring Boot version --branches string The branch pattern for branches to trigger CI / CD pipelines on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx delete</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_delete/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_delete/</guid>
      <description> jx delete Deletes one or many resources
Synopsis Deletes one or many resources.
jx delete TYPE [flags]  Examples  # Delete an environment jx delete env staging  SEE ALSO  jx - jx is a command line tool for working with Jenkins X jx delete addon - Deletes one or many addons jx delete contexts - Deletes one or more kubernetes contexts jx delete environment - Deletes one or more environments jx delete git - Deletes one or many git resources jx delete jenkins - Deletes one or many jenkins resources jx delete repo - Deletes one or more git repositories  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx delete addon</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_delete_addon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_delete_addon/</guid>
      <description> jx delete addon Deletes one or many addons
Synopsis Deletes one or many addons
jx delete addon  Options  -p, --purge Removes the release name from helm so it can be reused again (default true)  SEE ALSO  jx delete - Deletes one or many resources jx delete addon gitea - Deletes the gitea addon  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx delete addon gitea</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_delete_addon_gitea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_delete_addon_gitea/</guid>
      <description> jx delete addon gitea Deletes the gitea addon
Synopsis Deletes the gitea addon
jx delete addon gitea  Examples  # Deletes the gitea addon jx delete addon gitea  Options  -p, --purge Removes the release name from helm so it can be reused again (default true) -r, --release string The chart release name (default &amp;quot;gitea&amp;quot;)  SEE ALSO  jx delete addon - Deletes one or many addons  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx delete contexts</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_delete_contexts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_delete_contexts/</guid>
      <description> jx delete contexts Deletes one or more kubernetes contexts
Synopsis Deletes one or more kubernetes contexts.
jx delete contexts  Examples  # Deletes a context for a cluster that no longer exists jx delete context something # Deletes all contexts containing the word cheese # selecting them all by default jx delete ctx -a cheese  Options  -a, --all Selects all the matched contexts  SEE ALSO  jx delete - Deletes one or many resources  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx delete environment</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_delete_environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_delete_environment/</guid>
      <description> jx delete environment Deletes one or more environments
Synopsis Deletes one or more environments.
jx delete environment  Examples  # Deletes an environment jx delete env staging  Options  -n, --namespace Delete the namespace for the Environment too?  SEE ALSO  jx delete - Deletes one or many resources  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx delete git</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_delete_git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_delete_git/</guid>
      <description> jx delete git Deletes one or many git resources
Synopsis Deletes one or many git resources
jx delete git  SEE ALSO  jx delete - Deletes one or many resources jx delete git server - Deletes one or more git server jx delete git token - Deletes one or more api tokens for a user on a git server  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx delete git server</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_delete_git_server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_delete_git_server/</guid>
      <description> jx delete git server Deletes one or more git server
Synopsis Deletes one or more git servers from your local settings
jx delete git server  Examples  # Deletes a git provider jx delete git server MyProvider  Options  -i, --ignore-missing Silently ignore attempts to remove a git server name that does not exist  SEE ALSO  jx delete git - Deletes one or many git resources  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx delete git token</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_delete_git_token/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_delete_git_token/</guid>
      <description> jx delete git token Deletes one or more api tokens for a user on a git server
Synopsis Deletes one or more git tokens from your local settings
jx delete git token  Examples  # Deletes a git user token jx delete git token -n local myusername  Options  -n, --name string The name of the git server to add a user -u, --url string The URL of the git server to add a user  SEE ALSO  jx delete git - Deletes one or many git resources  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx delete jenkins</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_delete_jenkins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_delete_jenkins/</guid>
      <description> jx delete jenkins Deletes one or many jenkins resources
Synopsis Deletes one or many jenkins resources
jx delete jenkins  SEE ALSO  jx delete - Deletes one or many resources jx delete jenkins user - Deletes one or more jenkins user api tokens  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx delete jenkins user</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_delete_jenkins_user/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_delete_jenkins_user/</guid>
      <description> jx delete jenkins user Deletes one or more jenkins user api tokens
Synopsis Deletes one or more jenkins user tokens from your local settings
jx delete jenkins user  Examples  # Deletes a git provider jx delete git server MyProvider  Options  -n, --name string The name of the git server to add a user -u, --url string The URL of the git server to add a user  SEE ALSO  jx delete jenkins - Deletes one or many jenkins resources  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx delete repo</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_delete_repo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_delete_repo/</guid>
      <description> jx delete repo Deletes one or more git repositories
Synopsis Deletes one or more repositories.
This command will require the delete repo role on your Persona Access Token.
Note that command will ask for confirmation before doing anything!
jx delete repo  Examples  # Selects the repositories to delete from the given github organisation jx delete repo --github --org myname # Selects all the repositories in organisation myname that contain &#39;foo&#39; # you get a chance to select which ones not to delete jx delete repo --github --org myname --all --filter foo  Options  --all If selecting projects to import from a git provider this defaults to selecting them all --filter string If selecting projects to import from a git provider this filters the list of repositories -g, --git-host string The Git server host if not using GitHub --github If you wis to pick the repositories from GitHub to import -n, --name stringArray Specify the git repository names to delete -o, --org string Specify the git provider organisation that includes the repository to delete  SEE ALSO  jx delete - Deletes one or many resources  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx edit</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_edit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_edit/</guid>
      <description> jx edit Edit a resource
Synopsis Edit a resource
jx edit [flags]  Examples  # Lets edit the staging Environment jx edit env staging  SEE ALSO  jx - jx is a command line tool for working with Jenkins X jx edit environment - Edits an Environment which is used to promote your Team&amp;rsquo;s Applications via Continuous Delivery  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx edit environment</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_edit_environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_edit_environment/</guid>
      <description>jx edit environment Edits an Environment which is used to promote your Team&amp;rsquo;s Applications via Continuous Delivery
Synopsis Edits a new Environment An Environment maps to a kubernetes cluster and namespace and is a place that your team&amp;rsquo;s applications can be promoted to via Continous Delivery.
You can optionally use GitOps to manage the configuration of an Environment by storing all configuration in a git repository and then only changing it via Pull Requests and CI / CD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx environment</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_environment/</guid>
      <description> jx environment View or change the current environment in the current kubernetes cluster
Synopsis Displays or changes the current environment.
jx environment  Examples  # view the current environment jx env -b # pick which environment to switch to jx env # Change the current environment to &#39;staging&#39; jx env staging  Options  -b, --batch-mode In batch mode the command never prompts for user input --headless Enable headless operation if using browser automation --verbose Enable verbose logging  SEE ALSO  jx - jx is a command line tool for working with Jenkins X  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx get</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_get/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_get/</guid>
      <description> jx get Display one or many resources
Synopsis Display one or many resources.
Valid resource types include:
 environments (aka &amp;lsquo;env&amp;rsquo;)
 pipelines (aka &amp;lsquo;pipe&amp;rsquo;)
 urls (aka &amp;lsquo;url&amp;rsquo;)  jx get TYPE [flags]  Examples  # List all pipeines jx get pipeline # List all URLs for services in the current namespace jx get url  SEE ALSO  jx - jx is a command line tool for working with Jenkins X jx get activities - Display one or many Activities on projects jx get addons - Lists the addons jx get applications - Display one or many Applications and their versions jx get build - Display one or many build resources jx get environments - Display one or many Environments jx get git - Display the current registered git service URLs jx get pipelines - Display one or many Pipelines jx get urls - Display one or many URLs  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx get activities</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_get_activities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_get_activities/</guid>
      <description> jx get activities Display one or many Activities on projects
Synopsis Display the current activities for one more more projects.
jx get activities  Examples  # List the current activities for all applications in the current team jx get activities # List the current activities for application &#39;foo&#39; jx get act foo  Options  -b, --build string The build number to filter on -f, --filter string Text to filter the pipeline names  SEE ALSO  jx get - Display one or many resources  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx get addons</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_get_addons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_get_addons/</guid>
      <description> jx get addons Lists the addons
Synopsis Display the available addons
jx get addons [flags]  Examples  # List all the possible addons jx get addon  SEE ALSO  jx get - Display one or many resources  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx get applications</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_get_applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_get_applications/</guid>
      <description> jx get applications Display one or many Applications and their versions
Synopsis Display applications across environments.
jx get applications  Examples  # List applications for all environments jx get apps # List applications and their URLs for all environments jx get apps -u  Options  -u, --url Show the URLs rather than pod numbers  SEE ALSO  jx get - Display one or many resources  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx get build</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_get_build/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_get_build/</guid>
      <description> jx get build Display one or many build resources
Synopsis Display one or many resources.
Valid resource types include:
 environments (aka &amp;lsquo;env&amp;rsquo;)
 pipelines (aka &amp;lsquo;pipe&amp;rsquo;)
 urls (aka &amp;lsquo;url&amp;rsquo;)  jx get build [flags]  Examples  # List all pipeines jx get pipeline # List all URLs for services in the current namespace jx get url  SEE ALSO  jx get - Display one or many resources jx get build log - Display a build log  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx get build log</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_get_build_log/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_get_build_log/</guid>
      <description> jx get build log Display a build log
Synopsis Display the git server URLs.
jx get build log [flags]  Examples  # List all registered git server URLs jx get git  Options  -f, --filter string Filters all the available jobs by those that contain the given text -t, --tail Tails the build log to the current terminal (default true)  SEE ALSO  jx get build - Display one or many build resources  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx get environments</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_get_environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_get_environments/</guid>
      <description> jx get environments Display one or many Environments
Synopsis Display one or many environments.
jx get environments  Examples  # List all environments jx get environments # List all environments using the shorter alias jx get env  Options  -o, --output string The output format such as &#39;yaml&#39; -p, --promote string Filters the environments by promotion strategy. Possible values: Auto, Manual, Never  SEE ALSO  jx get - Display one or many resources  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx get git</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_get_git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_get_git/</guid>
      <description> jx get git Display the current registered git service URLs
Synopsis Display the git server URLs.
jx get git [flags]  Examples  # List all registered git server URLs jx get git  SEE ALSO  jx get - Display one or many resources  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx get pipelines</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_get_pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_get_pipelines/</guid>
      <description> jx get pipelines Display one or many Pipelines
Synopsis Display one or many pipelines.
jx get pipelines [flags]  Examples  # List all pipelines jx get pipeline  Options  -o, --output string The output format such as &#39;yaml&#39;  SEE ALSO  jx get - Display one or many resources  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx get urls</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_get_urls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_get_urls/</guid>
      <description> jx get urls Display one or many URLs
Synopsis Display one or many URLs from the running services.
jx get urls [flags]  Examples  # List all URLs in this namespace jx get url  Options  -e, --env string Specifies the Environment name to look inside -n, --namespace string Specifies the namespace name to look inside  SEE ALSO  jx get - Display one or many resources  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx import</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_import/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_import/</guid>
      <description>jx import Imports a local project or git repository into Jenkins
Synopsis Imports a local folder or git repository into Jenkins X.
If you specify no other options or arguments then the current directory is imported. Or you can use &amp;lsquo;&amp;ndash;dir&amp;rsquo; to specify a directory to import.
You can specify the git URL as an argument.
jx import  Examples  # Import the current folder jx import # Import a different folder jx import /foo/bar # Import a git repository from a URL jx import --url https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx init</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_init/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_init/</guid>
      <description>jx init Init Jenkins X
Synopsis This command installs the Jenkins X platform on a connected kubernetes cluster
jx init  Examples  jx init  Options  -b, --batch-mode In batch mode the command never prompts for user input --domain string Domain to expose ingress endpoints. Example: jenkinsx.io --draft-client-only Only install draft client --headless Enable headless operation if using browser automation --helm-client-only Only install helm client --provider string Cloud service providing the kubernetes cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx install</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_install/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_install/</guid>
      <description>jx install Install Jenkins X in the current Kubernetes cluster
Synopsis Installs the Jenkins X platform on a Kubernetes cluster
Requires a &amp;ndash;git-username and either &amp;ndash;git-token or &amp;ndash;git-password that can be used to create a new token. This is so the Jenkins X platform can git tag your releases
jx install [flags]  Examples  # Default installer which uses interactive prompts to generate git secrets jx install # Install with a GitHub personal access token jx install --git-username jenkins-x-bot --git-token 9fdbd2d070cd81eb12bca87861bcd850  Options  -b, --batch-mode In batch mode the command never prompts for user input --cleanup-temp-files Cleans up any temporary values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx logs</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_logs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_logs/</guid>
      <description>jx logs Tails the log of the latest pod for a deployment
Synopsis Tails the logs of the newest pod for a Deployment.
jx logs [deployment]  Examples  # Tails the log of the latest pod in deployment myapp jx logs myapp # Tails the log of the container foo in the latest pod in deployment myapp jx logs myapp -c foo  Options  -c, --container string The name of the container to log -f, --filter string Filters the available deployments if no deployment argument is provided -n, --namespace string the namespace to look for the Deployment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx namespace</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_namespace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_namespace/</guid>
      <description> jx namespace View or change the current namespace context in the current kubernetes cluster
Synopsis Displays or changes the current namespace.
jx namespace  Examples  # view the current namespace jx ns -b # to select the namespace to switch to jx ns # Change the current namespace to &#39;cheese&#39; jx ns cheese  Options  -b, --batch-mode In batch mode the command never prompts for user input --headless Enable headless operation if using browser automation --verbose Enable verbose logging  SEE ALSO  jx - jx is a command line tool for working with Jenkins X  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx open</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_open/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_open/</guid>
      <description> jx open Open a service in a browser
Synopsis Opens a named service in the browser.
You can use the &amp;lsquo;&amp;ndash;url&amp;rsquo; argument to just display the URL without opening it
jx open  Examples  # Open the Nexus console in a browser jx open jenkins-x-sonatype-nexus # Print the Nexus console URL but do not open a browser jx open jenkins-x-sonatype-nexus -u # List all the service URLs jx open  Options  -e, --env string Specifies the Environment name to look inside -n, --namespace string Specifies the namespace name to look inside -u, --url Only displays and the URL and does not open the browser  SEE ALSO  jx - jx is a command line tool for working with Jenkins X  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx preview</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_preview/</guid>
      <description>jx preview Creates or updates a Preview Environment for the current version of an application
Synopsis Creates or updates a Preview environment for the given Pull Request or Branch
jx preview  Examples  # Create or updates the Preview Environment for the Pull Request jx preview  Options  -a, --app string The Application to promote -c, --cluster string The Kubernetes cluster for the Environment. If blank and a namespace is specified assumes the current cluster --dir string The source directory used to detect the git source URL and reference --domain string Domain to expose ingress endpoints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx promote</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_promote/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_promote/</guid>
      <description>jx promote Promotes a version of an application to an environment
Synopsis Promotes a version of an application to zero to many permanent environments.
jx promote [application]  Examples  # Promote a version of the current application to staging # discovering the application name from the source code jx promote --version 1.2.3 --env staging # Promote a version of the myapp application to production jx promote myapp --version 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx prompt</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_prompt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_prompt/</guid>
      <description> jx prompt Generate the command line prompt for the current team and environment
Synopsis Generate a command prompt for the current namespace and kubernetes context.
jx prompt  Examples  # Generate the current prompt jx prompt # Enable the prompt for bash PS1=&amp;quot;[\u@\h \W \$(jx prompt)]\$ &amp;quot; # Enable the prompt for zsh PROMPT=&#39;$(jx prompt)&#39;$PROMPT  Options  --context-color stringArray The color for the kubernetes context (default [cyan]) -d, --divider string The divider between the team and environment for the prompt (default &amp;quot;:&amp;quot;) -i, --icon Uses an icon for the label in the prompt -l, --label string The label for the prompt (default &amp;quot;k8s&amp;quot;) --label-color stringArray The color for the label (default [blue]) --namespace-color stringArray The color for the namespace (default [green]) --no-label Disables the use of the label in the prompt -p, --prefix string The prefix text for the prompt -s, --separator string The separator between the label and the rest of the prompt (default &amp;quot;:&amp;quot;) -x, --suffix string The suffix text for the prompt (default &amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;quot;)  SEE ALSO  jx - jx is a command line tool for working with Jenkins X  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx rsh</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_rsh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_rsh/</guid>
      <description>jx rsh Opens a terminal in a pod or runs a command in the pod
Synopsis Opens a terminal or runs a command in a pods container
jx rsh [deploymentOrPodName]  Examples  # Open a terminal in the first container of the foo deployment&#39;s latest pod jx rsh foo # Opens a terminal in the cheese container in the latest pod in the foo deployment jx rsh -c cheese foo  Options  -c, --container string The name of the container to log -n, --namespace string the namespace to look for the Deployment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx shell</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_shell/</guid>
      <description> jx shell Create a sub shell so that changes to the kubernetes context, namespace or environment remain local to the shell
Synopsis Create a sub shell so that changes to the kubernetes context, namespace or environment remain local to the shell.
jx shell  Examples  # create a new shell where the context changes are local to the shell only jx shell # create a new shell using a specific named context jx shell prod-cluster # ends the current shell and returns to the previous kubernetes context exit  Options  -b, --batch-mode In batch mode the command never prompts for user input --headless Enable headless operation if using browser automation --verbose Enable verbose logging  SEE ALSO  jx - jx is a command line tool for working with Jenkins X  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx start</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_start/</guid>
      <description> jx start Starts a process such as a pipeline
Synopsis Starts a process such as a Jenkins pipeline.
jx start TYPE [flags]  Examples  # Start a pipeline jx start pipeline foo  SEE ALSO  jx - jx is a command line tool for working with Jenkins X jx start pipeline - Starts one or more pipelines  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx start pipeline</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_start_pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_start_pipeline/</guid>
      <description> jx start pipeline Starts one or more pipelines
Synopsis Starts the pipeline build.
jx start pipeline [flags]  Examples  # Start a pipeline jx start pipeline foo # Select the pipeline to start jx start pipeline # Select the pipeline to start and tail the log jx start pipeline -t  Options  -f, --filter string Filters all the available jobs by those that contain the given text -t, --tail Tails the build log to the current terminal  SEE ALSO  jx start - Starts a process such as a pipeline  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx step</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_step/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_step/</guid>
      <description> jx step pipeline steps
Synopsis pipeline steps
jx step  SEE ALSO  jx - jx is a command line tool for working with Jenkins X jx step changelog - Creates a changelog for a git tag jx step nexus - nexus [command] jx step pr - pipeline step pr jx step tag - Creates a git tag and pushes to remote repo  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx step changelog</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_step_changelog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_step_changelog/</guid>
      <description>jx step changelog Creates a changelog for a git tag
Synopsis Generates a Changelog for the latest tag
This command will generate a Changelog as markdown for the git commit range given. If you are using GitHub it will also update the GitHub Release with the changelog. You can disable that by passing&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;update-release=false&amp;rsquo;
If you have just created a git tag this command will try default to the changes between the last tag and the previous one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx step nexus</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_step_nexus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_step_nexus/</guid>
      <description> jx step nexus nexus [command]
Synopsis nexus [command]
jx step nexus  SEE ALSO  jx step - pipeline steps jx step nexus drop - Drops a staging nexus release jx step nexus release - Releases a staging nexus release  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx step nexus drop</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_step_nexus_drop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_step_nexus_drop/</guid>
      <description> jx step nexus drop Drops a staging nexus release
Synopsis This pipeline step command drops a Staging Nexus Repository
jx step nexus drop  Examples  jx step nexus drop  SEE ALSO  jx step nexus - nexus [command]  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx step nexus release</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_step_nexus_release/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_step_nexus_release/</guid>
      <description> jx step nexus release Releases a staging nexus release
Synopsis This pipeline step command releases a Nexus staging repository
jx step nexus release  Examples  jx step nexus release  Options  -d, --drop-on-fail Should we drop the repository on failure (default true)  SEE ALSO  jx step nexus - nexus [command]  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx step pr</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_step_pr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_step_pr/</guid>
      <description> jx step pr pipeline step pr
Synopsis pipeline step pr
jx step pr  Options  -b, --batch-mode In batch mode the command never prompts for user input --headless Enable headless operation if using browser automation --verbose Enable verbose logging  SEE ALSO  jx step - pipeline steps jx step pr comment - pipeline step pr comment  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx step pr comment</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_step_pr_comment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_step_pr_comment/</guid>
      <description> jx step pr comment pipeline step pr comment
Synopsis pipeline step pr comment
jx step pr comment  Options  -b, --batch-mode In batch mode the command never prompts for user input -c, --comment string comment to add to the Pull Request --headless Enable headless operation if using browser automation -o, --owner string git organisation / owner -p, --pull-request string git pull request number -r, --repository string git repository --verbose Enable verbose logging  SEE ALSO  jx step pr - pipeline step pr  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx step tag</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_step_tag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_step_tag/</guid>
      <description>jx step tag Creates a git tag and pushes to remote repo
Synopsis This pipeline step command creates a git tag using a version number prefixed with &amp;lsquo;v&amp;rsquo; and pushes it to a remote origin repo.
This commands effectively runs:
git commit -a -m &amp;ldquo;release $(VERSION)&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash;allow-empty git tag -fa v$(VERSION) -m &amp;ldquo;Release version $(VERSION)&amp;rdquo; git push origin v$(VERSION)
jx step tag  Examples  jx step tag --version 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx uninstall</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_uninstall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_uninstall/</guid>
      <description> jx uninstall Uninstall the Jenkins X platform
Synopsis Uninstalls the Jenkins X platform from a kubernetes cluster
jx uninstall  Examples  # Uninstall the Jenkins X platform jx uninstall  SEE ALSO  jx - jx is a command line tool for working with Jenkins X  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx upgrade</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_upgrade/</guid>
      <description> jx upgrade Upgrades a resource
Synopsis Upgrade a the whole Jenkins-X platform.
jx upgrade [flags]  Examples  # upgrade the platform jx upgrade platform  SEE ALSO  jx - jx is a command line tool for working with Jenkins X jx upgrade platform - Upgrades the Jenkins X platform if there is a new release available  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx upgrade platform</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_upgrade_platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_upgrade_platform/</guid>
      <description> jx upgrade platform Upgrades the Jenkins X platform if there is a new release available
Synopsis Upgrades the Jenkins X platform if there is a newer release
jx upgrade platform  Examples  # Upgrades the Jenkins X platform jx upgrade platform  Options  -c, --chart string The Chart to upgrade (default &amp;quot;jenkins-x/jenkins-x-platform&amp;quot;) -n, --name string The release name (default &amp;quot;jenkins-x&amp;quot;) --namespace string The Namespace to promote to -v, --version string The Version to promote  SEE ALSO  jx upgrade - Upgrades a resource  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx version</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_version/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_version/</guid>
      <description> jx version Print the version information
Synopsis Print the version information
jx version  SEE ALSO  jx - jx is a command line tool for working with Jenkins X  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 11-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx delete env</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_delete_env/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 13:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_delete_env/</guid>
      <description> jx delete env Deletes one or more environments
Synopsis Deletes one or more environments.
jx delete env [flags]  Examples  # Deletes an environment jx delete env staging  Options  -h, --help help for env -n, --namespace Delete the namespace for the Environment too?  SEE ALSO  jx delete - Deletes one or many resources  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 9-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx get apps</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_get_apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 13:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_get_apps/</guid>
      <description> jx get apps Display one or many Applications and their versions
Synopsis Display applications across environments.
jx get apps [flags]  Examples  # List applications for all environments jx get apps # List applications and their URLs for all environments jx get apps -u  Options  -h, --help help for apps -u, --url Show the URLs rather than pod numbers  SEE ALSO  jx get - Display one or many resources  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 9-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx addon</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_addon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 13:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_addon/</guid>
      <description> jx addon Creates an addon
Synopsis Creates an addon
jx addon [flags]  Options  --helm-update Should we run helm update first to ensure we use the latest version (default true) -h, --help help for addon -n, --namespace string The Namespace to install into -r, --release string The chart release name (default &amp;quot;gitea&amp;quot;)  SEE ALSO  jx - jx is a command line tool for working with Jenkins X jx addon cdx - Create the CDX addon (a web console for working with CI / CD and Environments) jx addon gitea - Create a gitea addon for hosting git repositories  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 6-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx addon cdx</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_addon_cdx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 13:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_addon_cdx/</guid>
      <description> jx addon cdx Create the CDX addon (a web console for working with CI / CD and Environments)
Synopsis Creates the CDX addon
CDX provides unified Continuous Delivery Environment console to make it easier to do CI / CD and Environments across a number of microservices and teams
jx addon cdx [flags]  Examples  # Create the cdx addon jx create addon cdx  Options  -b, --batch-mode In batch mode the command never prompts for user input --headless Enable headless operation if using browser automation --helm-update Should we run helm update first to ensure we use the latest version (default true) -h, --help help for cdx -n, --namespace string The Namespace to install into -r, --release string The chart release name (default &amp;quot;gitea&amp;quot;) --verbose Enable verbose logging  SEE ALSO  jx addon - Creates an addon  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 6-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx addon gitea</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_addon_gitea/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 13:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_addon_gitea/</guid>
      <description>jx addon gitea Create a gitea addon for hosting git repositories
Synopsis Creates the gitea addon (hosted git server)
jx addon gitea [flags]  Examples  # Create the gitea addon jx create addon gitea  Options  --admin Should the new user created be an admin of the gitea server -b, --batch-mode In batch mode the command never prompts for user input -c, --chart string The name of the chart to use (default &amp;quot;jenkins-x/gitea&amp;quot;) -e, --email string The email address of the new user to create in gitea --headless Enable headless operation if using browser automation --helm-update Should we run helm update first to ensure we use the latest version (default true) -h, --help help for gitea -n, --namespace string The Namespace to install into --no-token If true disable trying to create a new token in the gitea server --no-user If true disable trying to create a new user in the gitea server -p, --password string The password for the user to create in gitea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx create jenkins user</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_jenkins_user/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 13:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_create_jenkins_user/</guid>
      <description> jx create jenkins user Adds a new user name and api token for a jenkins server server
Synopsis Creates a new user and API Token for the current Jenkins Server
jx create jenkins user [username] [flags]  Examples  # Add a new API Token for a user for the current Jenkins server # prompting the user to find and enter the API Token jx create jenkins token someUserName # Add a new API Token for a user for the current Jenkins server # using browser automation to login to the git server # with the username an password to find the API Token jx create jenkins token -p somePassword someUserName  Options  -t, --api-token string The API Token for the user -b, --batch-mode In batch mode the command never prompts for user input --headless Enable headless operation if using browser automation -h, --help help for user -n, --name string The name of the git server to add a user -p, --password string The User password to try automatically create a new API Token --timeout string The timeout if using browser automation to generate the API token (by passing username and password) -u, --url string The URL of the git server to add a user --verbose Enable verbose logging  SEE ALSO  jx create jenkins - Creates a jenkins resource  Auto generated by spf13/cobra on 6-Mar-2018 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jx metrics</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 13:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/commands/jx_metrics/</guid>
      <description>jx metrics Gets the metrics of the latest pod for a deployment
Synopsis Gets the metrics of the newest pod for a Deployment.
jx metrics [deployment] [flags]  Examples  # displays metrics of the latest pod in deployment myapp jx metrics myapp # Tails the metrics of the container foo in the latest pod in deployment myapp jx metrics myapp -c foo  Options  -d, --duration string The duration to query (e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>