<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About Jenkins X on Jenkins X</title>
    <link>https://jenkins-x.io/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About Jenkins X on Jenkins X</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jenkins-x.io/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Features</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/about/features/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/about/features/</guid>
      <description>Command Line Jenkins X comes with a handy jx command line tool to easily:
 install Jenkins X inside your existing kubernetes cluster create a new kubernetes cluster and install Jenkins X into it import projects into Jenkins X and their Continuous Delivery pipelines setup create new Spring Boot applications which get imported into Jenkins X and their Continuous Delivery pipelines setup  Pipelines Rather than having to have deep knowledge of the internals of Jenkins Pipeline, Jenkins X will default awesome pipelines for your projects that implements fully CI and CD using DevOps best practices</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/about/accelerate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/about/accelerate/</guid>
      <description>Jenkins X is an implementation heavily influence by the State of DevOps reports and more recently the Accelerate book from Nicole Forsgren, Jez Jumble and Gene Kim.
Years of gathering data from real world teams and organisations which has been analysed by inspiring thought leaders and data scientists from the DevOps world. The Accelerate book recommends a number of capabilites that Jenkins X is implementing so users gain the scientifically proven benefits, out of the box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concepts</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/about/concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/about/concepts/</guid>
      <description>Jenkins X is designed to make it simple for developers to work to DevOps principles and best practices. The approaches taken are based on the comprehensive research done for ACCELERATE: Building and Scaling High Performing Technology Organsiations
Principles &amp;ldquo;DevOps is a set of practices intended to reduce the time between committing a change to a system and the change being placed into normal production, while ensuring high quality.&amp;rdquo;
The goals of DevOps projects are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decisions</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/about/decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/about/decisions/</guid>
      <description>Decisions Jenkins X is an opinionated developer experience, here we will explain the background and decisions we have taken to help explain the reasons for these opinions. You may also want to take a look at the Accelerate page for details on how Jenkins X implements the capabilities recommended by
Kubernetes First is why Jenkins X is purely focussed on Kubernetes and is only inteded to run on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache License</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/about/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/about/license/</guid>
      <description>Jenkins X is released under the Apache 2.0 license.
Version 2.0, January 2004 http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
Terms and Conditions for use, reproduction, and distribution
1. Definitions “License” shall mean the terms and conditions for use, reproduction, and distribution as defined by Sections 1 through 9 of this document.
“Licensor” shall mean the copyright owner or entity authorized by the copyright owner that is granting the License.
“Legal Entity” shall mean the union of the acting entity and all other entities that control, are controlled by, or are under common control with that entity.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>