<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jenkins X – FAQ</title>
    <link>/docs/using-jx/faq/</link>
    <description>Recent content in FAQ on Jenkins X</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="/docs/using-jx/faq/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Jenkins X Pipelines Questions</title>
      <link>/docs/using-jx/faq/pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/using-jx/faq/pipelines/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        

&lt;p&gt;For more background see the guide on &lt;a href=&#34;/docs/concepts/jenkins-x-pipelines/&#34;&gt;Serverless Jenkins X Pipelines&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;a href=&#34;https://tekton.dev/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tekton&lt;/a&gt;. There is also the &lt;a href=&#34;/docs/reference/pipeline-syntax-reference/&#34;&gt;Jenkins X Pipelines Syntax Reference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-i-add-a-custom-step&#34;&gt;How do I add a custom step?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add a new custom step to your &lt;code&gt;jenkins-x.yml&lt;/code&gt; file see &lt;a href=&#34;/docs/concepts/jenkins-x-pipelines/#customizing-the-pipelines&#34;&gt;how to use the jx create step&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-jenkins-x-pipelines-compare-to-jenkins-pipelines&#34;&gt;How do Jenkins X Pipelines compare to Jenkins pipelines?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;/docs/concepts/jenkins-x-pipelines/#differences-to-jenkins-pipelines&#34;&gt;the differences between Jenkins X and Jenkins Pipelines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-i-get-ide-completion-editing-jenkins-x-yml&#34;&gt;How do I get IDE completion editing &lt;code&gt;jenkins-x.yml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the IDE guide for &lt;a href=&#34;/docs/concepts/jenkins-x-pipelines/#editing-in-vs-code&#34;&gt;IDEA&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;/docs/concepts/jenkins-x-pipelines/#editing-in-vs-code&#34;&gt;VS Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-environment-variables-are-available-by-default-inside-a-pipeline&#34;&gt;What environment variables are available by default inside a pipeline?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&#34;/docs/concepts/jenkins-x-pipelines/#default-environment-variables&#34;&gt;default environment variables created for pipeline steps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-there-a-reference-for-the-syntax&#34;&gt;Is there a reference for the syntax?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&#34;/docs/reference/pipeline-syntax-reference/&#34;&gt;Jenkins X Pipelines Syntax Reference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-i-mount-a-secret-or-configmap&#34;&gt;How do I mount a Secret or ConfigMap?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each step in a Jenkins X Pipeline in the &lt;code&gt;jenkins-x.yml&lt;/code&gt; file is basically a &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/generated/kubernetes-api/v1.15/#container-v1-core&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Container&lt;/a&gt; from kubernetes so you can specify the image, resource limitts, environment variables and mount them from a &lt;code&gt;ConfigMap&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Secret&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see &lt;a href=&#34;/docs/reference/pipeline-syntax-reference/#full-pipeline-definition-in-jenkins-x-yml&#34;&gt;an example of mounting a Secrett to an environment variable here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are inside a shell script you can also use the &lt;a href=&#34;/commands/jx_step_credential/&#34;&gt;jx step credential&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-i-mount-a-persistent-volume-in-my-pipeline&#34;&gt;Can I mount a Persistent Volume in my pipeline?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tekton already mounts a separate Persistent Volume for each build pod at &lt;code&gt;/workspace&lt;/code&gt; so the build results are kept around for a while until they are garbage collected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On most kubernetes clusters you cannot easily share a single Persistent Volume across multiple pods; so having a shared PV across builds isn&amp;rsquo;t generally easy or compatible. You can however add a step to populate your PV on startup from a cloud bucket and at the end of a pipeline copy data into a bucket to speed up caching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also do things like use Nexus as a network cache for fetching maven dependencies (which happens OOTB with Maven builds in Jenkins X) or add the Athens proxy for Go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully the Tekton community will figure out some even better caching solutions to speed up builds.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
