<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jenkins X - Cloud Native CI/CD Built On Kubernetes – Mentorship opportunities</title>
    <link>https://jenkins-x.io/community/maintainer_guide/mentorship/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mentorship opportunities on Jenkins X - Cloud Native CI/CD Built On Kubernetes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://jenkins-x.io/community/maintainer_guide/mentorship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Community: GSoC</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/community/maintainer_guide/mentorship/gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/community/maintainer_guide/mentorship/gsoc/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Jenkins X has participated in the Google Summer of code (GSoC) before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the process that Jenkins X will follow when applying for GSoC (timelines are subject to change, check the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/open-source/gsoc/timeline&#34;&gt;timeline&lt;/a&gt; section in the gsoc webpage).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publish a blog post announcing Jenkins X interest in applying to GSoC when the application is announced by Google
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this normally happens in November&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set a deadline when all project ideas are submitted for internal review by Jenkins X TOC
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to set the deadline internally for project list submission to February 1.
This is normally when the application opens for organizations.
The application remain open only for 2 weeks, so it&amp;rsquo;s better to have a list beforehand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decide internally on a list of projects and the mentors that are interested.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Projects with multiple mentors are more likely to be shortlisted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once the application is announced by Google, publish a blog post with the project ideas. A sample is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/blog/2022/02/20/gsoc2022-ideas/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submit the application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If selected by GSoC (results are announced in March), publish a follow up blog post.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This blog post is expected to help the GSoC applicants understand more about Jenkins X and what we are looking for in an ideal contributor. Check the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/blog/2022/03/12/gsoc2022-followup/&#34;&gt;follow up blog from 2022&lt;/a&gt; to get an idea.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It helps the contributors and the mentors if a project template is provided.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After the project proposal deadline (April), decide on a list of contributors and rank the project proposals (the one at the top is the strongest proposal)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once Google announces the list of accepted proposals for Jenkins X (not all proposals ranked will get selected), mentors should discuss the project details (and time commitments) with the contributors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
