<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>关于 Jenkins X on Jenkins X</title>
    <link>http://jenkins-x.io/zh/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 关于 Jenkins X on Jenkins X</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-CN</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jenkins-x.io/zh/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Features</title>
      <link>http://jenkins-x.io/zh/about/features/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jenkins-x.io/zh/about/features/</guid>
      <description>Command Line Jenkins X comes with a handy jx command line tool to easily:
 install Jenkins X inside your existing kubernetes cluster create a new kubernetes cluster and install Jenkins X into it import projects into Jenkins X and their Continuous Delivery pipelines setup create new Spring Boot applications which get imported into Jenkins X and their Continuous Delivery pipelines setup  Pipelines Rather than having to have deep knowledge of the internals of Jenkins Pipeline, Jenkins X will default awesome pipelines for your projects that implements fully CI and CD using DevOps best practices</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concepts</title>
      <link>http://jenkins-x.io/zh/about/concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jenkins-x.io/zh/about/concepts/</guid>
      <description>Jenkins X is designed to make it simple for developers to work to DevOps principles and best practices.
Principles &amp;ldquo;DevOps is a set of practices intended to reduce the time between committing a change to a system and the change being placed into normal production, while ensuring high quality.&amp;rdquo;
The goals of DevOps projects are:
 Faster time to market Improved deployment frequency Shorter time between fixes Lower failure rate of releases Faster Mean Time To Recovery  High performing teams should be able to deploy multiple times per day compared to the industry average that falls between once per week and once per month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache License</title>
      <link>http://jenkins-x.io/zh/about/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jenkins-x.io/zh/about/license/</guid>
      <description>Jenkins X is released under the Apache 2.0 license.
Version 2.0, January 2004 http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
Terms and Conditions for use, reproduction, and distribution
1. Definitions “License” shall mean the terms and conditions for use, reproduction, and distribution as defined by Sections 1 through 9 of this document.
“Licensor” shall mean the copyright owner or entity authorized by the copyright owner that is granting the License.
“Legal Entity” shall mean the union of the acting entity and all other entities that control, are controlled by, or are under common control with that entity.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>