<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Faq on Jenkins X</title>
    <link>https://jenkins-x.io/categories/faq/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Faq on Jenkins X</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jenkins-x.io/categories/faq/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Common Problems</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/faq/issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/faq/issues/</guid>
      <description>We have tried to collate common issues here with work arounds. If your issue isn&amp;rsquo;t listed here please let us know.
Jenkins X does not startup If your install fails to start there could be a few different reasons why the Jenkins X pods don&amp;rsquo;t start.
Your cluster could be out of resources. You can check the spare resources on your cluster via jx status:
jx status  A common issue for pods not starting is if your cluster does not have a default storage class setup so that Persistent Volume Claims can be bound to Persistent Volumes as described in the install instructions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development Questions</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/faq/develop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/faq/develop/</guid>
      <description>How do I inject environment specific configuration? Each environment in Jenkins X is defined in a git repository; we use GitOps to manage all changes in each environment such as:
 adding/removing apps changing the version of an app (up or down) configuring any app with environment specific values   The first two items are defined in the env/requirements.yaml file in the git repository for your environment. the latter is defined in the env/values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Questions</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/faq/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/faq/faq/</guid>
      <description>We have tried to collate common issues here with work arounds. If your issue isn&amp;rsquo;t listed here please let us know.
Is Jenkins X Open Source? Yes! All of Jenkins X source code and artifacts are open source; either Apache or MIT and will always remain so!
How does Jenkins X compare to Jenkins? Jenkins X provides automated CI + CD for applications on kubernetes with GitOps promotion through environments and preview environments on Pull Requests .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup Questions</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/faq/setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/faq/setup/</guid>
      <description>How do I add a user to my Jenkins X installation? Jenkins X assumes each user has access to the same development kubernetes cluster that Jenkins X is running on.
If your user does not have access to the kubernetes cluster we need to setup their ~/.kube/config file so that they can access it.
If you are using Google&amp;rsquo;s GKE then you can browse the GKE Console to view all the clusters and click on the Connect button next to your development cluster and then that lets you copy/paste the command to connect to the cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Questions</title>
      <link>https://jenkins-x.io/faq/technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkins-x.io/faq/technology/</guid>
      <description>What is Helm? helm is the open source package manager for Kubernetes.
It works like other package mangers (brew, yum, npm etc) where there&amp;rsquo;s one or more repositories with packages to install (called charts in helm to keep with the nautical kubernetes theme) which can be searched/installed and upgraded.
A helm chart is basically a versioned tarball of kubernetes yaml which can be easily installed on any kubnernetes cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>